爸  他才不蠢
He ain't stupid, Daddy!
爸...
Daddy!
过来
Ohh! Come on!
马上回家去
Uhh! Get on back home. Now!
快点  你还有活要干呢!走吧
Get on up. You got work to do. Come on!
快点  给我回去
Come on, get on home!
你放开他
Uhh! You let him alone!
爸爸  别这样
Daddy, no!
我要打扁你  你这个臭德国佬!
I will bust you open, you dirty German!
你骂我什么?
What'd you call me?
我在法国和德国人打过仗
I fought the Germans in France.
非常艰巨的阵地相持战
And I fought them in the trenches.
上帝保佑!那些可怕的事情别再发生了
And I pray to God no one ever has to see the things that I saw.
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend.
爸  等等!
Daddy, wait!
爸  等等我
Daddy, wait.
阿道夫・希特勒把德国变成了战争机器
Adolf Hitler builds the German military machine
整个欧洲都陷入了战火
and drags all of Europe into war.
即使希特勒占领了法国  但美国仍拒绝加入战局
But even while France falls to Hitler, America still refuses to join the fighting.
(米歇空军基地)
(一九四一年一月  长岛)
麦考利和沃克在哪儿?
Where's McCawley and Walker?
还在进行飞行训练
Still training, sir.
丹尼!让我们教他们什么叫开飞机
All right, Danny. Now let's show them how to fly.
来"老鹰捉小鸡"  准备好了吗?
We're gonna play chicken. You ready?
这可不是农场的飞机  我不玩
This ain't the farm, and these ain't no cropdusters. I'm not playing chicken with you.
别当胆小鬼  让我告诉你
Now don't be a baby. I'll tell you what...
我不玩儿  雷夫
I'm not doing it, Rafe.
那我冲你来了  你可以躲开
Well, I'm coming right at you. You can turn,
也可以和我相撞  你看着办吧
or you can hit me. It's up to you.
搞什么?
What the...
完了
Oh, boy.
你为什么总是害我  雷夫?
Why you always busting my ass, Rafe?
你从哪边过?
Which way you going?
我想从右边  不  左边  我从左边
I guess I'll go right. No, uh, left. I'll go left.
我们从左边  是吗?
OK, we're going left, right?
嗯  是右边  右边吗?
Ri... uh, right. Right?
右边是指我们从右边过  还是指我们从左边过?
Right like we're going right, or right like we're going left?
你把我搅糊涂了!我不知道  你说吧
Well, now you got me all mixed up! I don't know. Make up your mind.
上帝啊  雷夫  我们从右边!右边!
God, Rafe, we're going right! Righty- tighty!
他们真是王牌飞行员
Those are some smooth aces.
你说什么?
Did you say something?
我告诉你们  这两个乡巴佬被禁飞了!
'Cause let me tell you, those farm boys are grounded!
是的  长官  决不允许拿军用飞机冒险
Yes, sir, an entirely unacceptable use... of m- m- military aircraft, sir.
- 拿我的帽子来  - 是的  长官
- Get my hat. - Yes, sir.
叫这些亡命徒去杜立特办公室
Get those hedge- hoppers in Doolittle's office.
已经训练两年了
After two years of training...
请你不要来送我
could you... not come see me off?
现在跟你道别已经够难过了
Because, uh... saying good- bye to you once is hard enough.
来
Here.
戴上这个
Take this.
我戴上它好看吗?
You think it looks good on me?
我很快就会回来的
I will come back.
你不是叫她别来吗?
I thought you said you told her not to come.
没错
Yeah, I did.
那你干嘛还在找她?
Why you looking for her then?
这是个考验
It's my test.
我叫她别来她还是来了
If I tell her not to come, and she comes anyway...
就说明她真的非常爱我
then I... I know she loves me.
请五十七站台的乘客上车
All aboard! Track 57!
如果我发生意外
If, uh, anything happens to me...
你一定告诉她  好吗?
I want you to be the one to tell her. All right?
为了我和她
You just make sure and come back for the both of us,
你要活着回来
all right?
- 等我回来  再见了  - 好的
- See you when I get back. - Yeah.
好好干  雷夫
Good hunting, Rafe.
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
伊芙琳!伊芙琳!嘿
Evelyn! Evelyn! Evelyn. Hey!
她爱我
She loves me.
德国空军开始轰炸伦敦市中心
The German Luftwaffe relent lessly bombards downtown London...
英国皇家空军为了捍卫领空
while Churchill's Royal Air Force is
陷入艰辛的苦战
in a deadly struggle to maintain control of the British skies.
简直是破铜烂铁
This is a real mess.
麦考利中尉报到  长官
Lieutenant McCawley reporting for duty, sir.
很好  我们先安排你住下
We'll get you settled into your quarters.
然后带你去看看你要飞的破烂飞机
And then introduce you to the crate you'll be flying.
长官  看你们都在这忙着
If you all are patching up bullet holes
我还是直接上飞机吧
here maybe we ought to skip housekeeping and get me in an airplane.
两架飞机没有返航  只剩十一架
Two didn't come back, sir. We counted only eleven.
象你这样的美国人都急着去送死吗? 飞行员
Are all Yanks as anxious as you to get themselves killed, Pilot Officer?
我不想送死  我只想打仗
Not anxious to die, sir. Just anxious to matter.
这是你的战斗机
This is yours.
他是好样的
Good chap.
直到着陆关闭引擎后才闭上眼睛
Didn't die till he'd landed and shut down his engine.
请坐  先生们
Please be seated, gentlemen.
我的心情很沉重
I'm afraid I'm in a bad mood.
刚才邱吉尔和斯大林问我  我也要问问你们
Churchill and Stalin are asking me what I'm asking you.
美国还要假装世界大战没有发生多久?
How long is America going to pretend the world is not at war?
我们提供了大量的食品和油料  总统先生  就我所知
We've increased food and oil shipments, Mr. President and as far as I know
他们需要坦克、战斗机、大炮、子弹还有士兵
What they really need are tanks, planes bullets, bombs, and men to fight.
可美国人还是认为希特勒和
But our people think Hitler and his
他的纳粹党仅仅只是欧洲的问题
Nazi thugs are Europe's problem.
我忘了拿扳手
Forgot my wrenches.
这真的很尴尬
That would definitely be embarrassing.
你好  我忘了拿扳手
Yeah. Ha. Forgot my wrenches.
他真的没有必要离开呀
He really doesn't have to leave.
是啊
No.
我要跟朋友出去  那么
I, uh, I'm just going out with the girls, so...
回头见吧
I guess I'll see you later.
好的  回头见
Yeah. All right. Yeah, all right. I'll see you around.
见鬼
Shit.
伊芙琳
Evelyn.
你见过珍珠港的日落吗?
Have you ever seen Pearl Harbor at sunset?
当然
Of course.
是从空中看的吗?
from the air?
你知道吗  为这我会被踢出军队的
You know, I could get kicked out of the military for this.
真的吗?
Really?
真的  趴下来
Yeah. Stay down.
夏威夷人叫这"瓦伊摩米"  意思是"珍珠海"
The Hawaiians called this harbor Wai Momi. It means "water of pearls."
真是美极了!
It's so beautiful.
我爸带我飞过几次
My dad took me up a couple of times.
千万别学他那样翻斤头  你们怎么称呼在空中翻斤头?
Just don't do what he did. What do you call it when you flip over?
空中翻滚?
A barrel roll?
- 对  - 我不会学他的
- Yeah. - I won't.
你觉得怎样?
What do you think?
很过瘾
I like that.
那架飞机应该在一小时之前就返航的
Hey! That plane was supposed to be back here an hour ago!
快  躲在伞库里
Quick, hide in the parachute hangar.
我的心跳得好快
My heart is pounding.
丹尼  昨天晚上  不  那样不行
Danny, last night... No, that's terrible.
丹尼  我们要好好谈谈
Danny, we need to talk about this.
- 长官  伊芙琳!  - 丹尼  嘿
- Sir.- Evelyn! - Danny. Hey.
我一夜都没合眼  一直想见你
I didn't sleep a wink last night. I had to see you.
我知道昨晚太疯狂了  但我不后悔  你呢?
Last night was crazy, I know, but... I'm not sorry. Are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我过的很愉快  但
Danny, I had a wonderful time last night. I...
这一切都太快了
It's just all too fast.
伊芙琳  今天早上我坐在沙滩上
Listen, Evelyn, I was just down at the beach this morning
望着升起的太阳
and I watched the sun rise...
心里想  这一切将重新开始
and I knew that everything was gonna be different.
就从今天开始
That this was the start of something new.
就在此时此刻
In this place, in this moment.
我不在乎别人的议论
And I don't care what anybody else says, you know?
为什么我有这种感觉?
How can I not feel this way?
因为我喜欢你
I kinda like you.
是吗?
Oh, you do?
你的领带歪了
You have your tie on crooked.
一切都会好起来  好吗?
Everything's gonna be all right, OK?
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be all right.
你坐飞机去过瓦胡岛吗?
Do you have any ain'tours going through the valley of Oahu?
懂我的意思吗?
You do?
- 止血钳  - 止血钳
- Hemostat. - Hemostat.
放心  看着我  你会没事的  会没事的
All right, look at me. You're going to be all right. You're going to be all right.
我们轰炸了他们的军舰和机场
现在要摧毁备用机场
我需要弹药!我需要弹药!我要更多的弹药
I need more ammo! I need more ammo, ladies! I need more ammo!
厄尔  那些飞机能飞吗?
Earl! We good to go?
差不多  但是
Mostly, but...
趴下来!天哪!找掩体!
Get down! Shit! Get cover!
我的天
Jesus!
你们快过来!厄尔  快进来
Come on, you guys! Earl, get in here!
散弹枪不管用!
Sergeant! We need more than a shotgun!
还有武器和弹药吗?
You got any other weapons for coverfire?
在那边的弹药库里!
Inside that ammo locker!
快点!走!走!
Come on! Go! Move it!
把枪拿出来!
Get the guns out!
你说飞机差不多能够飞  有什么问题吗?
You said the planes are mostly ready, but... but what?
这架抛锚  那架坏了  那架根本飞不了 只剩下四架可以飞
She's down, she's broke, she's shit. I got four left.
一架好的  两架缺弹药  一架缺油
One's good, two need ammo, one needs fuel.
快躲进掩体里面去  把子弹装好!
Fall out and load up in the bunker!
我们走!趴下来!快点!
Let's go! Get down! Move!
做好准备  开始干吧! 快趴下!
Get ready to roll this thing! Get down! Now!
安东尼  雷德  你们负责 50 高射炮
Anthony, Red, you stay here and man the fifty- caliber.
古斯  你去附近的掩体  掩护我们  好吗?
Gooz, get to the next bunker and lay down some coverfire. All right?
敌机来了
Planes.
我们要开枪吗?
Should we fire?
趴下来  妈的  别开火  冷静点  千万别开火
Stay down! God damn it! Hold your fire! Stay still! Nobody fire!
噢  天啊  噢  天啊
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
他们不知道我们在这儿
They don't know we're here.
- 别动  - 开火吗?
- Stay down. - Fire?
不  妈的  趴下  他们没发现我们  趴着别开枪
No, God damn it, stay down, stay still. Don't fire.
老天
Oh, God.
敌机没有炸弹了  我想他们要返航了
I don't see any ordnance. I think they're going home.
不
No.
他们还会回来的  地面上仍然有我们的飞机
They'll be back. We still got planes on the ground.
飞行员们听好
Pilots, listen up.
在跑道上一定要开足马力  别到头了才拉操纵杆
Get all the speed you can on the runway... don't get on the stick till the very end.
起飞后要低飞  在建筑物之间活动
In the air, stay low between the buildings.
如果被零式咬住尾巴  左右摇摆甩掉他
You see any Zero on your tail... wipe him off,
别傻愣着  好吗?要保持移动
don't freeze. all right? Just keep moving.
我们要设法分散他们
Try to separate them,
然后一架一架地消灭
take them out one by one.
P- 40 飞机没有零式飞机快  所以别和它比速度
P- 40s can't out run Zeros, so don't try.
只有靠技术超过它们
We have to outfly them.
高空轰炸机!他们非把机库炸平不可!
We got high- level bombers! They'll bust this hangar wide open!
拿上机枪走  走吧
Grab the fifties! Let's move!
珍 珠 港
(田纳西州  一九二三年)
德国佬  两点钟方向
German bandits at two o'clock!
全速前进
Increase throttle! Power dive!
你拼错了啦  雷夫
Spell it right, Rafe.
方向舵  应该是两个 D
"Rudder" is spelled with two Ds.
- 谢了  伙伴 - 哦  不客气
- Thanks, wingman. - Yeah, sure.
敌机来袭
Whoa, bandits!
打得好  丹尼
Crack shooting, Danny.
你也一样
Crack shooting, Rafe.
为了自由
Land of the free.
为了祖国
Home of the brave.
飞得帅呆了  老爸
Great flying, Dad
来吧  我教你开飞机
Come on. I'm gonna teach you how to fly.
我要坐前面
I get the front!
不  你得坐后面
No, you take the back.
我比较高  我应该坐前面
I'm bigger, and I should be in front.
我比你大  我还要教你呢
I'm older, and I'm teaching, so no.
哇  我们真像在飞一样啦!
Wow. It's like we're really flying.
我玩过好几次了
Yeah, I did it lots of times.
你去守住机关枪  我来减速
Come on, you man the guns. I'll give her some throttle.
我们要打落德国飞机
We gotta get those dirty German bandits.
噢  天啊
Oh, gosh!
快停下来  雷夫!
Hang on! Make it stop, Rafe!
我看我爸开过很多次  没事儿!
I've seen my dad do this lots of times, don't worry!
雷夫!
Rafe!
喔  我们飞起来了啦!
Oh, my gosh! We're flying!
我们飞起来了
We're flying!
我老爸饶不了我!快走
My dad's gonna kill me. Come on.
好耶
Yes! Whoo- hoo!
我们飞起来了!我们飞起来了!
We flew! We flew!
- 好耶  我是飞行员  - 我知道了
- Yeah! Yes! I'm a pilot! - I know!
我们飞起来了
We flew.
- 你这个没用的东西  - 爸爸
- You no- account boy! - Daddy...
我说过  别和这个笨蛋泡在一起
I done told you, you spend time playing with this stupid boy...
他不识字!你会一辈子没出息的
...can't read. you ain't never going to amount to nothing!
你们以为造价四万五千美元的战斗机
you believe that a $45,000 airplane...
是用来玩吗?
is there for your amusement?
不是  长官  我只是磨练技巧
No, sir. I was just trying... to keep my edge, Major.
上礼拜你玩空中翻筋斗
And when you did the outside loop last week...
也是为了磨练技巧吗?
what did you think that was? Honing your skills?
那不是飞行技巧!麦考利  是哗众取宠!
That's not training, McCawley. That's a stunt.
也是愚蠢和不负责的行为
And I personally consider it to be reckless... and irresponsible.
少校
Major...
怎么会啊
How could that be,
你可是那招
when you're famous for being the first man
的开山鼻祖
in the world ever to do it?
别跟我耍嘴皮子
Don't get cute with me, son.
我没有耍嘴皮子  长官
No, sir, I don't mean to be disrespectful.
请恕我直言  我只是认为
I just think that... well, I...
如果仅仅只是为了出风头  这是愚蠢和不负责的
It is reckless and irresponsible if you're just doing it to be a show- off.
但我这样是为了启发战友
But I was doing it to try to inspire the men, sir...
就像您当初启发我一样
in the way that you've inspired me.
有句成语能够用来形容我对您的钦佩
I believe the French even have a word for that...
法国人称之为
when the men get together to honor their leaders.
五体投地
They call it an homage, sir.
什么?
A what?
- 是五体投地  长官  - 这全是屁话  麦考利
- An homage, sir. - That's bullshit, McCawley!
但它是很中听的屁话
But it's very, very good bullshit.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir.
麦考利  你就像十五年前的我
McCawley, you remind me of myself fifteen years ago.
我们现在讨论一下这个
Which is why we need to discuss this.
坐下  年轻人
Have a seat, son.
英国人已经接受你加入雄鹰中队
The British have accepted you into the Eagle Squadron.
如果你愿意
You're on your way to England tomorrow...
明天就可以动身
if you still want to go.
飞行员是英国能否打退希特勒的关键
Just a few British pilots are all that stand
也决定着欧洲战场的走向
between Hitler and total victory in Europe.
他们非常需要援助
They're gonna need all the help they can get.
我马上出发  长官
Yes, sir. Well, I'm on my way.
按照规定  我应该要求你再慎重考虑一下
Just for the record... I'm supposed to ask you to reconsider.
长官?
Sir?
不管我们是否愿意
Sooner or later we're gonna be in this war...
...美国参战只是时间问题
whether we like it or not.
我们也需要优秀的飞行员
And I'm gonna need all of my best pilots.
所以我应该征询你是否愿意留下来
So it's my duty to ask you to stay.
少校  你会怎么做?
Major, what would you do?
如果是我
If it was me...
我会去
I'd go.
不会吧  我开始谢顶了?
Get out. Am I going bald right back here?
伙计  我是个帅小伙
Man, I am one good- looking son of a bitch.
可千万别死
Don't you ever die.
打仗你死不了  今晚你就要装一副快死的样子
Die. That's exactly the concept you gotta work tonight.
往眼睛上抹点儿丁香油
You put a drop of this clove oil under your eyes...
快忍不住的时候就去找护士
and you let them sting and well up.
做个深呼吸
You get your nurse alone, take a breath...
然后就热泪盈眶地对她说  宝贝
let her see your eyes listen and say,
他们训练我去打仗
"Baby, they're training me for war...
我生死难测
and I don't know what'll happen...
如果明天我一去不返
but if I die tomorrow...
我盼望今晚我俩能共度春宵
" I want to know that we lived all we could tonight."
来吧  伙计们  漂亮护士在等着咱们
Come on, guys! We got nurses waiting.
快点  再不走比利的头就要秃光了
Come on, before the rest of his hair falls out.
你为什么要做这样的决定?
How could you do this?
是杜立特点名派我去的
Well, Doolittle assigned me.
他希望我能够接受实战训练
He wanted me to get some real... real combat training in.
你想什么呢?
Well, guess what?
那儿可没有训练  只有战争
It's not training over there. It's war.
输家丢掉性命  赢家也一无所获
Where the losers die, and there aren't any winners...
大家都身心疲惫  就像我老爸那样
just guys who turn into broken- down wrecks... like my father.
我知道  我能理解  丹尼
Yeah, I understand that, Danny.
但是我觉得我有责仁去
But I feel like I got a duty to go.
见鬼  别和我扯什么责任
Don't preach to me about duty, damn it.
我和你一样都是军人
I wear the same uniform you do.
如果真有必要  我也会去
Now, if trouble wants me, I'm ready for it.
可你为什么要这样求之不得?
But why go looking for it?
听我说  丹尼  我快二十五岁了
God, Danny, come on. I'm gonna be twenty- five.
已经算是个老兵
I might as well be an old man.
我很快就只能当飞行教官了
They're gonna have me being a flight instructor.
我不想当教官
I don't wanna teach loops and barrel rolls.
我要开战斗机
I wanna be a combat fighter.
快点  护士们在等你们跳舞呢
Hey, come on! The nurses can't d- d- dance by themselves.
我们走吧
Let's go.
要是每天都和一百五十个穿内裤的小伙子们打交道
If the call of duty means seeing 150 men in their underwear every day...
我们可不嫌枯燥
...we are here to serve.
想不到能在纽约度周末
I can't believe it. Saturday night in New York City.
在家乡太没意思了!
Do you know what they're doing where I come from?
什么都不能做  只能逗牛玩
Nothing. Cow- tipping.
所以你来当海军
Well, that's why you joined the Navy, hong.
想开开眼界?
To get out of that dusty little town and see the world.
巴巴拉  我们是海军护士  可不是来旅游的
May I remind you, Barbara, we're Navy nurses, not tourists.
我当海军是来尽义务  还想找个男朋友
I joined to do my patriotic duty and to meet guys.
我也是
Me, too.
我们今晚玩个痛快!
Girls, we're gonna have so much fun tonight in the city.
给大家讲讲你的故事吧  伊芙琳
You've gotta tell them the story, Evelyn.
什么?
What?
说呀  告诉我们
Oh, come on. Tell us.
噢  说来话长
Oh, it's such a long story.
我们时间多的是
We got time.
我亲眼目睹哦
I saw it happen.
那是四个星期前
Well, it was about four weeks ago...
你认为怎样更好点?
What do you think is b- b- better?
都打在一边  还是分开打?
All in the one cheek, or spreading them out?
好吧
OK.
福斯科・安东尼
Fusco Anthony.
你没事吧?老兄
You all right, buddy?
甜心  真的要打针吗?
Sweetie, do you really have to do this?
我在军营可不会染上黄热病
I'm not gonna get yellow fever in my barracks.
不会吗?如果你愿意  可以让她打
No? If you'd rather, she can do it.
喔  喔  稍微等一下
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Just give me a minute.
亲爱的  上头说要给你们打  我们就得打
Honey, the government says stick them, we stick them.
雷德  你没事吧?
Uh! Hey, Red, you allright?
四号  测验视力
Eye exam number four?
医生  我都检查过十几次啦!
Listen, Doc, I have passed a dozen medical checks.
你要这样写  我就飞不成了
You write that, they won't let me fly.
很抱歉  年轻人
Sorry, son. I'm gonna fail.
(不合格)
糟糕  他们会折断我的翅膀
They're gonna take my wings away.
不会的  放轻松
No, they won't. Just relax.
读最后一行
Read the bottom line, please.
再背一遍最后一行  放心
Just keep practicing the bottom line. And don't worry.
我在后面
I'm right behind you.
谢谢
Thank
下一个
Next.
小姐
Ma'am.
J、L、M、K、P、O、E、T、X
JLMKPOETX
简直像老鹰的眼睛一样
Eyes like an eagle, ma'am.
慢点儿  飞行员  别看下边的
Slow down, flyboy. And, instead of the bottom,
读最上面一行   用双眼看
read the very top. Both eyes.
"C"  抱歉  "J"
Yeah. "C"...sorry, "J."
"C"、"W"
Ahem. "C"..."W." "W."
"Q"  "Q"  "Q"
请再读一遍最后一行
Read the bottom line again, please.
这次从右向左  而且间隔着读
But read it right to left and every other letter.
"E"、"X"
"E."Heh. "X."
"X""E"
护士小姐  我看得很清楚
X- E, ma'am. Ma'am, I know how this looks.
抱歉  中尉  真的很抱歉
I'm sorry, Lieutenant, I really am.
陆军和海军的都要求视力达到二点零
But Army and Navy requires 20/20 vision.
我的眼睛没有问题  我看得见
Oh, I... it's... it's not a problem with my eyes, I can see.
我的意思是  我的眼睛棒极了
I mean, I can see.
我可以一枪打死狂奔的野兔
I mean, I can hit a running rabbit with a $3.00 pistol.
我只是阅读字母有点困难  仅此而已
I got a problem with letters, that's all.
那只有先去上学
Well, maybe after some schooling...
再回来复查
you could come back and take the test again.
不  我上过学
No, I had schooling. I mean,
老师也拿我没办法
I... the teachers just never knew what to make of it.
只是字母而已  有的时候我常把
It's just letters.
它们的顺序弄颠倒  就是这样
I mix them up sometimes. That's all.
我的意思是  我只是把它们倒过来读
I mean, I just get them backward sometimes.
你看  我的数学、航空理论
L- look here. Uh, my... my math and...
还有口试  成绩都是优
and spacial reasoning and my verbal scores are all excellent.
但是你的写作成绩才刚及格
But you barely passed the written exam.
毕竟他及格了  总该我了吗?
Yeah, but he did pass it. So, is it my turn now?
还没有  你再等一下
No, you'll wait your turn.
好的  护士小姐
Yes, ma'am.
护士小姐  我不是来这儿教语言的
Ma'am, I- I'm never gonna be an English teacher.
我来这儿是为了当飞行员
But I know why I'm here. To be a pilot.
鬼才拿着课本上天打仗
And you don't dogfight with manuals. You don't fly with gauges.
我是说  开飞机关键得看感觉敏锐
I mean, it's all about feeling and speed...
反应迅速  还有是否能够与飞机融为一体
and letting that plane become like a part... of your body.
没人说阅读能力差  就当不了好飞行员
And that manual... says that a guy who's a slow reader can't be a good pilot.
档案上都说我是这儿的最棒的飞行员
That file says I'm the best pilot in this room.
护士小姐  求求你  别让我停飞
Ma'am, please, don't take my wings.
嗯  我感到很为难
Well, I felt so bad.
伊芙琳  到三号台去
Evelyn, rotate to station three.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
放他过关了
I passed him.
一会儿  这个飞行员又来了
So, then this cocky pilot comes back.
哎  小伙子  你是新兵?
Say, fella, are you enlisted?
是的
Yeah.
"是的"? 年轻人  你在和军官说话吗?
"Yeah"? Boy, you're talking to an officer.
是  长官  对不起  长官
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
- 把档案给我  - 是  长官
- Give me that file. - Yes, sir.
- 稍息 - 是  长官
- Parade rest. - Yes, sir.
护士小姐  我还没来得及谢谢你
Ma'am, I didn't get a chance to thank you.
裤子脱下来
Drop your skivvies.
啊  哦  好吧
Ah, oh, OK.
像这样?
Just like this?
很好
That's fine.
他的屁股很翘
He did have a very cute butt.
我知道您本不该让我过关的  但却您帮了我
You know, I know you didn't have to pass me and you did.
我以为你不明白我的意思  但是你却很清楚
And I just... I didn't think you'd understand, and you did.
知道吗  你还没感谢我呢
You know, you still haven't said thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我想知道您为什么帮我?  我只是很好奇
Why'd you do it? I mean, I'm just curious.
您现在是我的偶像了
You're like my hero now.
事实上  我父亲曾经是飞行员  我知道
Actually, my father was a pilot. And, um, I've seen first- hand what happens...
飞行员停飞的滋味
when a pilot loses his wings.
知道吗  您父亲也是我的偶像了
You know what? Your father's my hero, then, too.
作为一名军官  我想今晚请你
In fact, as an officer, I think it'd by my duty...
我的新偶像的女儿吃饭  是我应该做的
...to take my new hero's daughter out tonight just to...
- 啊!  - 有点儿深了吧?
- aah! - Gosh, did I poke too deep?
您好象扎进骨头了
I think you hit the bone there.
你太过分了
You are so mean.
难道您真不愿意
What? So is... is there any chance...
给我个机会?
that you might, kind of, sort of... you know, like me, or...
你想什么呢?
Oh, how did you guess?
我的头儿没教我体验这种感觉
They never taught us... how to deal with this... feeling.
什么感觉?
Wh- what feeling?
像是  这样
Well, it's kind of like... this.
他再放肆  我还要扎他
Well, he was getting fresh, so I poked him again.
嗨  罗密欧  我可不想找罪受
All right, Romeo. I want to get this over with.
等一下
Hold on a second.
我真的很想"舔"你
Miss... I really, really lick you.
他说什么?
What did he mean?
喜欢你  我舌头打结了
Like you. I didn't mean to say that. And I just, um...
我很想请你一起"送"饭
I just want to ask you, please, if I can donate dinner.
他开始语无伦次了
He started to act very strange.
我郑重地邀请你
Or, well, buy you dinner.
这不是你的档案
This isn't your chart.
不  这是那个家伙的  我想他落下了
Whoa. No. That's the, uh, this, uh, fellow over here's. I think he left.
你打过针了?
Have you already had this shot?
是的  嗯  已经打过一次了
Yeah, well, once... already.
嗯  我想  我的意思是  我可以约你出去吗?
Well, I wanted... I mean, can I ask you out?
不行
No!
突然  他一头栽到地上
And he just went wham!
噢!你对他怎么了?
Oh! What'd you do to him?
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
噢  老天  你没事吧?
Oh, my God. Are you OK?
嗯  没事  我没事  很好
Yeah, I'm fine, I feel great.
这样能起保护作用
This is just standard precautionary... thing.
看  我搞到些好东西  一瓶正宗的法国香槟
Look, I got some, uh, genuine French champagne... from France.
我想  也许我们该好好庆祝一下
I thought, you know, maybe we could celebrate.
庆祝什么?
Celebrate what?
噢  我也不知道  怎么说呢  庆祝你成了我的偶像
Oh, I don't know. Uh, well, you being my hero, for one.
好吧  为什么不呢?
OK. Why not?
我很感激你  感谢你
So, uh, ahem... I wanted to thank you. And I just wanted to, uh...
你让我通过了体检
put your mind at ease about passing me...
因为我真的想为国家尽一份力
because I really do think you did this country a service.
我的意思是  我是一名王牌飞行员
I mean, I'm... I am a great flier.
要说你缺点的话  那就是骄傲
And if you have a fault, which you obviously don't, it's modesty
不  如果说我有缺点  那就是直率
No. If I have a fault, it's candor.
你真的很
You are just so...
瓶塞崩着我了
Cork just got away from me.
天啊
God
天啊  噢  真疼
God, oh, it hurts.
疼死啦
It hurts something fierce.
对不起
I'm sorry.
噢  噢  流血了
Ohh... Oh, it's bleeding.
天啊
God.
- 躺下  - 我总是惹事生非
- Lay still. - I ruined everything.
- 别乱动  - 好痛
- Lay still. - Oh, it hurts.
- 噢!太凉啦!  - 冰块能止血
- Ow! It's cold. - It'll stop the bleeding.
我无法喘气
Yeah. I can't breathe.
躺好
Lay still.
你美得真叫人心疼
You are so beautiful it hurts.
是你的鼻子疼
It's your nose that hurts.
不  是我的心疼
No. I think it's my heart.
于是我吻了他
And then I kissed him.
伊芙琳  这是我听过最浪漫的故事
Oh, Evelyn. That's the most romantic story I ever heard.
这也是我这辈子最浪漫的四个星期又两天
It's been the most romantic four weeks and two days of my life.
我好羡慕你
Oh, I'm so jealous.
见到你真好  护士小姐
Hello, Lieutenant. It's good to see you.
我也是  中尉
You, too, Lieutenant.
挑一只手
Pick a hand.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
那只手有什么?
What's in your other hand?
是我的
Mine.
我花了六小时才折好
Well, it took me six hours to fold these.
介绍一下我的朋友  雷夫
I want you to meet my friends.
这是玛莎、巴巴拉、桑得拉
Rafe, this is Martha, Barbara, Sandra...
嗨  我是贝蒂
Hi. I'm Betty. Hi.
你的朋友呢?
Would you happen to have any friends?
随便选吧
Huh. Take your pick.
如果仗打起来  而我光荣负伤
We ever get in this war and something happens to me...
有你这样温柔的姑娘照顾我
I can't tell you how good it makes me feel to know...
让我恢复健康  那种感觉真的是太棒了
...that someone as sweet as you will be there to nurse me back to health.
可我们还没参战呢
Good, but we're not in the war yet.
嗨  那都是玩笑
OK. That was a bad line.
我  我是雷德  雷德
I'm... I'm Red, Red...
奇怪
S- s- s- s- strange.
你姓奇怪吗?
Your last name's Strange?
她是你的了
Yeah. She's all yours, soldier.
不  我姓温
No. It... it's Winkle.
雷德真有女人缘
Red is such a ladiesg man.
你总是结巴?
Do you always stutter?
不  只是在
No. Only when I'm...
她上勾了
She's totally buying it.
- 紧张的时候?  - 是啊
- Nervous?  - Yeah.
为什么我碰不上漂亮妞?
Why can't I get something like that? Hello. Hi.
丹尼和姑娘在一起太腼腆
Danny seems kind of shy around the girls.
他不是腼腆
Tsk. It's not that he's shy.
他只是  缺乏自信
He's just, ahem... a little unsure of himself, you know.
是他老爸呵斥的结果
His old man used to run him down a lot.
一上飞机  他就判若两人
Get him in a plane, he's sure of himself.
他是我的好兄弟  好朋友
He's like my brother. He's like my best friend.
如同我的右手
He's my right hand.
可现在你的手滑到我的腰部以下了
Which at the moment is a long way south of my waist.
对不起  我滑的太低了
Oh, I'm sorry. I guess I lost a little altitude.
是啊  我想你是的
Yeah, I guess you did.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我们得好好聊聊
You and me, we got to talk.
听说海军要派我们去珍珠港
So, the rumor is the Navy's shipping us to Pearl Harbor.
那挺好啊
Well, won't be so bad.
那儿离战场很远
It's about as far from the fighting as you can get.
可以享受一下温暖的阳光
You'll get a suntan.
也许你也会被调到那儿
So maybe the Army'll post you guys there, too.
你是一个特别了不起的女人
You... are a super special woman.
他们把我训练成彪悍的勇士
they're... they're training me... to be a big bad warrior, and, well...
明天可能就去出生入死
So, I mean, you never know what might happen tomorrow
谁知道会发生什么  你了解吗?  所以
... or... or any day after that, you know? So...
今晚我们应该有点特别的
God, we need to make tonight super special.
你哭什么?
Why are you crying?
我怕再也见不到你了
I guess it's the thought... that I might not ever get to see you again.
别哭啦  宝贝儿  今晚我是你的
Dry your eyes, toots. Tonight, you're mine.
今晚我不想到人多的地方去  我希望和你单独在一起
I don't want to be with a crowd tonight. I just want to be alone with you.
去看看月光下的纽约港?
How does New York Harbor by moonlight sound?
你想当坏蛋?
Are you gonna be a bad influence?
干吗不当个坏蛋呢?
Of course I'm a bad influence.
我们是军官
Let's see if we can commandeer this vessel...
可以征募这艘船
'cause we're, uh, officers of the U.S. Government.
别高兴的太早
Not for long, we won't be.
也许将来我们能坐这艘船旅行
One day, we'll take a trip on a boat like that.
你喜欢这艘船?
Would you like that?
在大厅里参加鸡尾酒会
We'll be dressing for cocktails and walk into the grand salon.
没有人谈论战争  大家都随着舞曲翩翩翩翩起舞
No one's talking about war. They're just dancing to Cole Porter.
我要穿晚礼服
I'll have to get a tux.
是啊
Yeah.
上来  开船了
Come on. There you go. All aboard.
我不是这个意思
You're out of your mind.
是啊  小心  坐好
Oh, yeah. Careful now. Here, sit down.
看我的
Now let's see here.
快到了
Ah! There we go.
我要让你登上你喜欢的船
See, this is as close as I could get you to your ship.
怎么样?
So, at least I tried, right?
我已经很满足了  这太好了
Actually, you know what? This is better.
老天  你真美啊
Yeah, it is. God, you're pretty.
(上  下)
往后我们会怎么样?雷夫
What's gonna become of us all, Rafe?
嗯  我们左右不了未来  对吗?
Well, the future's not exactly in our hands, is it?
是的  你是对的
No. I guess you're right.
天啊  你没事儿吧?
Oh, my God! Are you all right?
没事儿  你呢?
Yeah, are you?
计划中可没有这出
That was not part of the date.
- 小心地面  - 喔  谢谢
- Watch your step. - Oh, thank you.
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
伙计们  快上来吧
Guys, come up! Come on up!
我们在321号房
Come up! We're in 321.
我要跟你说一件事
There's something I got to tell you.
你对我没有秘密可言
Well, you got no secrets from me, Lieutenant.
我看过你的体格检查表  知道你的一切
I've seen your medical chart.
是坏消息?还是有难言之处?
This can't be good, or it wouldn't be so hard to say.
是啊
Yep.
我要被调走
I got to go away.
我们都要被调走
We're all going away. Yeah...
没错
Yep.
但是我是去打仗  明天就动身
but I'm going to the war... tomorrow.
我要加入飞鹰中队
I'm flying with the Eagle Squadron.
他们需要美国飞行员
It's an outfit the British started for American pilots.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是为美国军队服役  他们怎么能命令你去英国?
You're in the U.S. Army. How could they order you to go?
他们没有下命令  是我自愿的
They didn't order me. I volunteered.
我让你通过体检  是我放你过关的
But I passed you. I let you through.
现在你却自愿去最危险的地方?
And now you volunteer... for the most dangerous place you could go?
这和你没关系  你没有责任
It's not your responsibility, not your choice.
飞行曾经是我唯一的梦想
Flying's the only thing I ever wanted to do.
对我来说  我之所以活着  是为了
I mean, everything in my life has led me up to this point.
能够与你相遇
Meeting you.
我爱你
I love you.
我深深地爱着你
I love you so much.
我们进去吧
Let's go inside.
好的  等等  我不能这样做
All right. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
对不起  我只是
Just... I...
我不能这样做  我的意思是  我是非常渴望
See,I can't do this. I mean, I mean, I can. I... I want to.
你知道我并不是假装高尚
I'm not trying to be noble, you know.
或者谎称我不知道要发生什么
Or not saying I know what would happen or just...
我最好还是别说了
... I need to stop talking.
我只是  我只是不想
I just... I just don't want...
我只是不想跟别人一样
I just don't want it to be like everybody else.
今晚我不想
I don't want you to have anything about tonight...
给你留下任何遗憾
that you regret.
今晚对我一生至关重要
I mean, it's been the most
我不想破坏它
incredible night of my life... and I don't want to ruin that.
你当然不会破坏它
Oh, you couldn't ruin it.
如果我只能再活一晚  我也要与你共度
If I had one more night to live, I'd want to spend it with you.
这也是我的期盼
See, that's what I want to come home to.
这就是我一生的梦想
That's what I want to have to think about and dream about.
我要回来与你共度美好的生活
I want to know that the best part of my life... is still ahead of me.
不要
Look. Don't, um...
我们必须更积极些
We have to do more.
援助英国和苏联
Send the Brits and Russians more of our ships
更多的军舰和防空武器
and anti- aircraft weapons.
继续从太平洋舰队调拨?
And keep cannibalizing the Pacific Fleet?
还有更好的选择吗?
What choice do we have?
我们在制造冰箱  敌人却一直在制造炸弹
We're building refrigerators while our enemies build bombs.
战争已经不可避免了
掩盖事实只是失败
美军停止供应石油  切断了我们的生命线
我们只能维持十八个月
没有别的选择  只有战争
只有发动大规模的袭击
我们有这样的能力吗？
必须一仗消灭太平洋舰队
就在珍珠港
太令人激动了
This is so exciting.
珍珠港有大约一百多艘军舰
You know there's about one hundred ships on Pearl.
每一艘有多少水手?
How many sailors per ship?
那要看情况而定  军舰上的水手比潜艇上的多
It depends. More on a battle ship than a sub.
平均下来  有两千个?
But say, on average... 2,000?
加上飞行员、陆战队员  还有基地后勤
Then there's the flyers, the marines, base personnel.
我还在算水兵人数
I'm still working on the sailors.
反正我们的机率很高
Girls, I think the odds are in your favor.
是啊  一比四千
Yeah, like 4,000 to one.
这儿是天堂
It's paradise.
海滩上见了  帅哥们
See you on the beach, boys!
我们在夏威夷耶
We're in Hawaii!
嘿!你别在我的飞机上画奶子
Hey! You're not supposed to paint titties on the side of my airplanes.
要画也不能一大一小
And if you do, don't make them lopsided.
真玩意儿就是这样  厄尔
They were lopsided, Earl.
瞧  书上说  不能在礁石和暗桩处冲浪
Look, it says right here."Never ride waves amongst rocks or submerged pilings."
看  不能那样干
See, it says you shouldn't do that.
你怎么能知道哪有暗礁哪没有?
How do you know they're submerged if they're submerged?
古斯  你到底在干什么?
Gooz, what in the hell are you doing?
为他修冲浪板
Just trying to fix this surfboard thing.
被礁石撞坏了
He keeps taking chunks off his nose on the rocks.
放假的时候还要继续搞我的新发明  古斯水平舵
On my day off, I'm working on my new invention, the Gooz Cruise Fin.
我要发财啦! 所有的冲浪板都需要加装我的水平舵
I'm gonna be a rich fella. Every surfboard in the nation's gonna need one.
你最好打扫干净
Yeah? Well, you're gonna need a broom.
瞧瞧新来的菜鸟
Check out these new recruits.
嗨  哈
Hi. Aloha.
你们是飞行员吗?
You all pilots?
好像很复杂  上面有不少开关和按钮
We're working on it. It's a lot of switches and stuff.
太平洋的骄傲
Pride of the Pacific.
你们是谁?
Who are you?
空中杀手
Terrors of the skies.
欢迎  小姐们
Welcome, ladies.
等我解决了这个黑屁股  再带你们逛逛
I have to deal with toasty sunburnt fanny before I can show you around.
亲爱的伊芙琳 一切都出乎我的意料
Ow! Dear Evelyn. It's different than I thought it would be here.
这儿很冷、冷得刺骨
It's cold... so cold it goes deep into your bones.
但有一股暖流在我的胸中涌动  那就是我们的爱情
There is one place I can go to find warmth. That is to think of you.
我祈祷能早日回到你的身旁
I just wish I could be back there with you.
在这很难交到朋友
It's not easy making friends.
两天前  一对皇家飞行员夫妇  还和我们一起喝啤酒
Two days ago, I had a beer... with a couple of the RAF pilots.
昨天他们双双阵亡
Yesterday, both of them got killed.
亲爱的雷夫  我对你的思念难以叙说
Dear Rafe. I miss you so much.
千山万水将我们阻隔
It's so strange to be half a world away from you.
我咬住他了
I'm right on his tail!
打下一架
Got one!
黄昏  我注视着斜阳
Every night I look at the sunset...
希望留住最后的余辉
and try to draw the last ounce of heat from its long day...
用我的心温暖远方的爱人
and send it from my heart to yours.
家人吗?
Family?
女友  长官  我的意中人
Girl, sir. The girl.
许多人责怪美国人不参战
A lot of people frown on the Yanks for not being in this war yet.
我只想说  要是每个美国军人都跟你一样
I'd just like to say... if there are many more back home like you...
谁都不敢与美国为敌
God help anyone who goes to war with America.
礼仪分队  持枪!
Atten- hut! Attention on deck!
太平洋舰队总司令金梅尔上将登舰
Admiral Kimmel... Commander- in- Chief, Pacific Fleet, on deck.
士气很高昂  上校
Sharp presentation, Captain.
谢谢  将军
Thank you, Admiral Kimmel.
已经四个月了
For four months now Washington's been
华盛顿闭口不谈日本的威胁
blowing pink smoke about the threat from Japan.
这可能会影响我们的士气  我特别强调不能放松警惕
Could make us lose our fighting edge. I'm determined not to let that happen.
对不起  上校  将军  华盛顿急电
With your permission, Captain. Admiral, urgent, from Washington.
太平洋舰队正在积极准备对抗日本人
I'm supposed to keep this fleet...
保卫覆盖半个地球的太平洋
battle- ready to take on the Japanese... cover half the damn globe.
现在他们却要调十二艘驱逐舰到大西洋
Now they want me to transfer another
他们不知道我们也面临危险吗?
twelve destroyers to the Atlantic. Don't they know what we're facing out here?
他们认为欧洲的战事是最紧要的
They feel Europe is the greater danger.
有人考虑夏威夷的危险吗?
I'm assuming these risk assessments include Hawaii?
珍珠港水浅  敌人不能实施鱼雷攻击
Pearl Harbor is too shallow for an aerial torpedo attack.
而且受到潜艇的保护
We're surrounded by sub nets.
唯一需要担心的是敌人破坏我们的飞机
All we need worry about is sabotage...
所以我们把飞机集中起来  方便保护
so we bunched our planes together to make them easier to protect.
距离是天然的屏障  将军
Distance is our ally, Admiral.
你们分析了所有的可能性  对吗?
You analysts got it all figured out, don't you?
聪明的敌人常常会出其不意痛击你自以为很安全的地方
The smart enemy hits you exactly where you think you're safe.
我从观光飞机上
拍到军舰和空军基地的照片
这些军舰都停靠在一起
那是最明显的目标
为了适应水深我们改装了鱼雷
加装了木鳍
鱼雷就可以在浅水中攻击
趁珍珠港还没有苏醒
我们要发起猛烈的攻击
我修理了液压和电器系统  长官
In coming! I fixed the hydraulics and electrics, sir,
但是来不及修理油管
but the oil hoses still need attention.
启动引擎吧
Just crank it, lan!
祝你好运  长官
God speed you, sir.
红队  攻击轰炸机  蓝队  盯住战斗机
Red section, take the bombers. Blue section, look out for the fighters.
轰炸机在前方  咱们给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Bombers dead ahead. Let's dropin and give them a reception.
红二号  跟着我  爬高  攻击领头的轰炸机
Red Two, follow my lead, high side. Go right at the lead bomber.
好的  红一号
Following you, Red One.
打得好
Good hit! Good hit!
红一号  转回来攻击敌机
Red One, coming around, reset for the kill.
我锁定中间那一架
I have the middle bomber.
开火
Hammer down!
打中了  打得好  红二号
We got him. Nice shot, Red Two.
正前方有两架敌机
I got two M.E. s dead ahead.
我盯着他  让我来
I'm on him. I'm on his tail.
开火
Hammer down.
我打下一架
I got one of them!
我又打下一架
I got another one.
红一号  你的后面有一组编队
Red One, you got fighters all over your tail!
我受到攻击!我受到攻击!
I'm under fire! I'm taking fire!
红一号  快逃走  赶快拉高
Red One, get out of there. Pull up! Pull up!
油管破裂
Argh! I got an oil leak.
我什么也看不到了
Can't see a damn thing!
无法跳伞!座舱罩卡死了  我跳不出去
I can't bail! My canopy's stuck! I can't bail out!
敌机向我开火  红二号
He's on my tail, Red Two.
我被击中了!我被击中了!
I'm hit! I'm hit!
遇难信号!发信号!
Mayday! Mayday!
噢  我的天
Oh, my God.
我不想去教堂
I'm no good at church.
你怎么了?亲爱的
What do you mean, sweetie?
每当我走进去  开始忏悔
When I'm up there getting my slate wiped clean...
我就想到我还会做错事儿
I can't help I'm thinking how to dirty it up again.
这有什么关系
Wow, this from a virgin!
我要去清点备用品
I got to inventory supplies.
烦死了  能安静一会儿吗?
Kill me now. Could you be any more boring?
别管她  她要写信给雷夫
Don't bother. Sunday, she writes Rafe...
平常写五页  假日写十页
ten pages instead of the usual five.
我真想谈恋爱
Gosh, I wish I was in love.
嘿  亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
她讨厌我
She hates me.
见到你真好  雷德
Good to see you, Red.
我也是  贝蒂
Good to see you, too, Betty.
想一起兜兜风吗?
You wanna come for a ride?
来吧
Come on.
太好了  我来当你的司机
Yeah, I'll be your chauffeur.
狠狠地扁他  兄弟
That- a- boy! Be a mad dog!
做饭的  你还有两下子
You hit pretty hard... for a cook.
你赌谁赢?沃克
All right, Walker, who you got?
快点!要打完了
Come on! Get out there now!
我赌厨子
I'll take the cook.
为什么?你想输钱吗?
Why? You don't like money?
我赌五块
I'll put five on it.
好
Done.
对手是机师? 那家伙是头野牛  不好对付
Against a mechanic? That guy craps rivets.
刚从机舱里面出来感觉怎样?
How's it feel up from the engine room?
阳光很刺眼吧  眼睛睁不开吧?
Sunlight bothering you?
他打得很猛!移动!移动!
Ow. Man, he's getting all busted up!
过来  我告诉你  坐下来
Come here, we gotta talk. Get down here.
他伤不了你  他伤不了你
He can't hurt us. He can hurt us.
他伤得了我  我流血了
He can hurt us, he cut us. We bleeding.
流血?
Bleeding?
那只是小伤  看看这个
That's a scratch. See this?
黑哥们儿可都把血汗钱押在你身上了
This is the hard- earned greenbacks of every pot- scrubbing chop in this fleet.
要是你输了我们可就完了
Now if we don't win. Teeny here has to find another battle ship!
我不能空着手回亚利桑纳号
I'm not going back to the Arizona empty- handed.
别担心你的钱
Don't worry about the money.
我要把这家伙打回老家  让他滚回自己的机舱去
I'll send that smug engine- fixing snipe... back below decks where he belong.
加油  好兄弟!那混帐东西打了你老妈!是个婊子养的!
We the man! He slapped your mama! Be a son of a bitch!
你瞧  好耶  多利
Look at this! All right, Dorie!
够了  够了
That's enough. That's enough.
我的钱呢?
Oh! Where's my money?
不行  他作弊
Nah, fight's rigged.
咱们发了!哈!哈!哈!
We're rich! Ha ha ha!
你是怎么受伤的?
How'd you get this?
拳击
Boxing.
你赢了吗?
Did you win?
是的  护士小姐
Yes, ma'am.
赢了会怎样?
What do you get for winning?
获得尊严
Respect.
拳头能打出尊严来吗?
So, why do you have to fight with your fists to get respect?
我离开妈妈  离开德克萨斯  去当海军就是为了见见世面
I left my momma in Texas and joined the Navy to see the world...
为了做个受尊重的人
... become a man.
他们却叫我当厨子  甚至连厨子都不算
They made me a cook. Not even that.
还要为其他水兵收拾餐厅
I clean up after other sailors eat.
都两年了  我还没打过枪
Two years, they never even let me fire a weapon.
希望你永远不要碰枪
Well, let's hope you never have to.
是的  护士小姐
Yes, ma'am.
保重了  米勒士官
You take care, Petty Officer Miller.
你也是  护士小姐
You, too, ma'am.
你知道吗  他教我飞行
You know, he taught me to fly.
无论我遇到任何麻烦  我都不会束手无策
I always knew that no matter what trouble I got into... I'd never be in it alone.
他总会帮我渡过难关
He'd be there with me.
就是在天上他也逼着我超过别人
He was always pushing me to be better and faster.
他说你是个了不起的飞行员
He told me you were a great flier.
那天晚上他告诉我  他自愿去英国
It was the same night he told me he'd volunteered to go to England.
自愿?
Volunteered?
他跟我说他是被指派去的
He... he told me he'd been assigned.
他总是在设法保护我
He was always trying to protect me.
但是你知道吗?我看着镜子里面  穿着这身制服的自己
But you know what? I look at myself in the mirror in this uniform...
我都不知道我是谁
and I still don't know who I am.
我看起来像英雄吗?我感觉不是
I look like a hero... but I don't feel like it.
雷夫  他一向都是表里如一  不是吗?
Rafe... he always looked the part, didn't he?
他无法等到成为英雄的那一天了
He couldn't wait to be one.
敬雷夫・麦考利  最棒的飞行员
To Rafe McCawley. The best pilot...
我曾经最好的朋友
and the best friend I ever knew...
我一生最好的朋友
or ever will know.
敬雷夫
To Rafe.
(为国捐躯)
攻击训练正在进行中
为保证任务成功
高空轰炸及鱼雷攻击训练是极为重要的
只要偷袭顺利
美国人只有坐以待毙
制造大量的假情报麻痹美国人
特别要关注太平洋的主要目标
尤其是夏威夷  不能放松
你太英明了  山本大将
英明的人能避免战争
(一九四一年七月  华盛顿)
(海军司令部)
你看看
Look at this.
太平洋上到处都是日本人的电报
The Japanese are flooding the Pacific with radio traffic.
从巴拿马运河到东南亚都有
Everywhere from the Panama Canal to southeast Asia.
这不合乎逻辑  上校
There's no logical pattern, Captain.
对  这其中必有玄机
No. There's always logic.
他们知道我们在监听
They know we read their mail.
他们想让我们以为他们的舰队在向南移动
They're trying to make us think their fleet is moving south.
我不吃这一套  其中肯定有阴谋
I'm not buying it. Something, something's up.
否则  这也太明目张胆了
Otherwise, why would they take the trouble to bullshit me?
伊芙琳  我替你签收了这些信
Evelyn, I signed for these letters for you today.
从英国寄来的
They're from England.
雷夫的信
They're from Rafe.
很抱歉  伊芙琳  邮件比消息慢
I'm sorry, Evelyn. You know how long it takes mail to get here.
(三个月后)
(正在上映  卓别林 -  大独裁者)
(新闻剪辑)
美国还在等待日本的和平答复
America still awaits Japan's response to peace proposals.
野村大使抵达首都华盛顿
Ambassador Nomura arrives in Washington...
希望他的到来能够达成太平洋地区的和平协议
...in what could hopefully guarantee continued peace in the Pacific.
英国方面  邱吉尔宣称
On the British front, Churchill declares
只要美国支持我们就能获胜
"Give us the tools, and we will finish the job."
皇家空军在英吉利海峡誓死捍卫英国领空
The RAF has fought bravely against Hitler's ambition...
让希特勒的野心无法得逞
...to rule the skies over the Channel.
胜利来之不易  许多优秀飞行员献出了生命
Victory does not come without sacrifice.
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
丹尼  真巧啊
Danny. Hey. Some comedy, huh?
- 好久不见  - 我一直在进行训练
- It's been a while. - I've been logging a lot offlight hours.
我也一直碰不到你
I kinda been avoiding you, too.
你想不想  你
Look... Do you...
你想吗?
Do you want to?
好啊
Sure, yeah.
我记得我七岁那年  有一次
I remember this one time when I was like, seven years old.
那时候我老是爱做一些小玩艺儿
I was always building gadgets and things.
雷夫让我给他做一对翅膀  他就能像他老爸一样飞行
He wanted me to build him some wings so he could fly like his daddy.
我说没有引擎就飞不了
I told him you can't fly without some kind of engine.
但是他不肯听  他说  我叫你做就做
But he wouldn't listen. "Danny, never mind that, just build them anyway."
我只好照办了  我爬到谷仓上
So I did. And I'm up there...
帮他把大翅膀绑在身上
strapping these big old wings on his back...
那是我们用偷来的废纸、胶水和破布黏起来的
...that we made from paper and glue and these massive silk bloomers that we stole.
他的样子好蠢  我说  你不能这样从谷仓上跳下去
He looked so stupid, and I told him "You can't jump off the barn in these."
然后一声巨响  他摔断了一条腿
And bam! He busted his leg on a backhoe.
我好想念他
God, I miss him.
你想不到的是隔天他又爬上了屋顶
But don't you think that Rafe wasn't back up there next day.
包着石膏  还叫我把翅膀做一些调整
Cast and everything, telling me to make some adjustments on those wings.
你们看
Check this out!
塔希提岛  太平洋的中心  一千七百英里!帅呆了!
Crossroads of the Pacific. Tahiti -  1,700 miles! All right!
瞧   贝蒂
Say, Betty...
不要  快起来
No, Betty! Get up!
怎么回事?雷德
What's going on, Red?
你要站起来
Stand up, please.
为什么?
What do you mean?
你站起来  我跪着
Just stand up. Stand...
雷德  快点  我们有订位耶
Betty... Red, come on! We got a dinner reservation.
等一下行吗?
Can I get a minute?
你发神经了?
What's the matter, you sick?
我不能求婚吗?
Can a guy propose?!
我太多话吗? 有时候我很唠叨  对不起
Am I talking too much? Sometimes I do that, I'm sorry.
看!你们看这个!
Hold up! Look at this.
好了  别打扰他们  我们走吧
OK, let's get out of here. OK.
我该走了
I guess I should go.
别一等要三个月才能够再见到你  好吗?
Don't let it be three months before I see you again, all right?
我很开心
I had a good time.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
要我送你回家吗?
Do you want me to walk you home?
不用  我自己回去
No, I'll be fine.
好吧
No...of course.
晚安  丹尼
Good night.
晚安
我在想我能不能偶尔到你家
I was just wondering if maybe I could come by some time...
喝杯咖啡吃点东西什么的?
...get a cup of coffee or a piece of pie?
我这是在干嘛?好了
What am I doing? OK.
老天  你睡了
Oh! You were asleep.
对不起  你还穿着睡衣  丹尼
I'm sorry. Danny?
出了什么事?
Is something wrong?
没事  没什么  你好
No! Nothing's wrong. No problem. Hi!
是丹尼
It's just Danny.
我来是  你忘了这个
I... just... you... you forgot this.
噢  谢谢
Oh... thanks.
太麻烦你了  这么晚还送来
It was good of you to take the trouble to drop it over... now.
嗯  我想你可能用得着  你知道  也许明天一早
well, I thought you might need it. You know... maybe tomorrow morning.
你没带这个去上班
If... not that you wear this to work, but...
不过只是条手帕
No... it's a hankie.
对  没错
Right, right. Yeah.
我在想  也许哪天我能到你这来
Listen, I was thinking maybe I could come by some time...
如果我给你打电话  我能来吗?
if I gave you a call, could I come by some time?
如果你一旦有空的话  也许
Once, maybe... if you're not busy?
嗯  也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
好吧  好的  谢谢
OK, all right. Thanks.
晚安
Good- bye.
你是个白痴!
You are such an idiot!
昨晚你和丹尼怎么样?
Did you have fun last night?
不是你想象那样的
It wasn't how it looked.
就算是  也没关系的
And if it was, it'd be all right.
已经好几个月了  你得继续过日子
It's been months. It's time to move on.
我很好啊
I am moving on.
你别骗人  我知道  晚上我都听见你在哭泣
Ev, don't lie. All I know is, I hear you crying when you think I'm asleep.
我爸抛弃我们以后
When my dad left... I was too much for my mom to handle...
我妈就把我送到姑妈家
...so she sent me to live with my aunt.
我以为我这辈子就完蛋了  但是你并不知道接下来会怎样
I thought my life was over... But you don't know where it's all gonna lead.
如果我没有从家里面逃出来  谎报年龄
If I hadn't run away and lied about my age...
参加海军  我就不会认识雷德
...and enlisted in the Navy... I wouldn't have met Red,
现在他是我的未婚夫了
and... now he's my fiance.
我真不习惯这种称呼
Oh, God, I can't get used to that word.
不过才十二小时而已
It's only been twelve hours.
- 噢  贝蒂! - 小贝蒂比我们都厉害
- Oh, Betty! - Little Betty beat us all to the post.
这里是三号病房  你们也看到了  这儿没有病人
And this is ward three. As you can see, no patients.
欢迎到夏威夷  来  我带你们去玩
Welcome to Hawaii. Come on, I'll show you the bar.
桑得拉  咱们去逗逗她们  来啊
Sandra, new recruits to torture. Come on.
对不起  各位女士
Excuse me, ladies?
再过两年等我十九岁的时候  雷德就要买戒指给我
We're gonna wait two years until I'm nineteen and Red can buy me a ring.
雷夫让他最好的朋友照顾你
Rafe sent his best friend to tell you...
你应当振作起来了  继续活下去
...so you would be OK, so you can move on.
你还要继续生活下去
You gotta go on living, Ev.
雷德!喔  对不起!
Red! Whoo! Sorry!
永别了  雷夫
Bye, Rafe.
华盛顿  海军情报局
日本舰队失踪了
The Japanese Fleet is missing.
他们进行了无线电管制
They're operating under radio silence.
这是四天前  十月二十八日拍的照片
This footage was shot four days ago on October 28th.
我们的侦察机搜遍了太平洋
We're sending scout planes in wider vectors...
一无所获
all over the Pacific, but they get nothing.
他们可能隐藏在这里的某个地方
They could be anywhere in here.
我真不明白  两个航母编队能突然消失了?
I don't understand how two whole carrier divisions can just disappear.
安全
Clear!
都打偏了  一个偏外  一个偏内
Aw, we're all over the page. We got one wall- eyed and one pigeon- toed.
- 安东尼  调整一下六号机枪  - 好的
- Anthony, tap in number six. - All right.
古斯
Gooz,
- 调整一下三号机枪  - 好的
- tap in number three. - All right.
嘿  有客人来了
Hey. We got a visitor.
哦  那可不是海军制服
Oh... that ain't no Navy issue uniform, eh?
丹尼  是伊芙琳
Danny, it's Evelyn.
老天爷
Jesus!
你还好吧?
You all right?
很好
Yeah. Yeah.
我不好
No.
我想我大概爱上她了
I think I'm falling for her.
你知道的  我早就猜到了
Wow. You know, I saw this coming.
我从未想过  来得太突然了  情不自禁的
I didn't want this to happen. It just kind of did. Can't help it.
她总要嫁人  你是最合适的
Well, Danny, she's gotta be with somebody. It might as well be you.
你告诉我  如果你阵亡了  而你最好的兄弟却在搞你的女友
You telling me if you were dead and you saw your best buddy doing your girl...
你不会起死复生  狠狠地揍这个活着的臭小子一顿吧?
...you wouldn't come back and beat the living crap outta him?
托尼  给我闭嘴
Tony, back off.
我会死也不会放过他
I'd be back so fast.
丹尼重情重义  会照顾好她的
Danny's being a better friend taking care of her himself.
我也有女朋友
I got a girlfriend.
那太好了  我们走吧
That's great. Come on, fellas. Let's split.
丹尼  不管怎样这都是你和她的事了
Danny, whatever happens now is just about you and her.
别总想着雷夫
You gotta try and forget about Rafe.
小心点  好吗? 女人会蛊惑人心
Be careful, all right? Ladies... cloud the mind.
谢了  古斯
Thanks, Gooz.
不客气
You're welcome.
嘿  丹尼
Hey, Danny.
他们要去哪儿?
Where's everybody going?
他们在避嫌
Just being discreet.
好像大家都挺怪怪的
Does it seem like everybody's acting a little strange?
没有呀
No. Nah.
对
Right.
嗯  也许  也许是有一点吧
Well, maybe... maybe a little. Yeah.
这里的人都太闲了
Well, people in this outfit... have way too much time on their hands.
关于我们
Oh, yeah. I just hope they don't think
但愿他们别乱想得离谱
there's been something... going on between us, that's all.
没有啦  那就太尴尬了
Oh, no. I mean, no. That would be... embarrassing, right?
这里是檀香山广播电台
This is KGMB in Honolulu...
瓦胡岛又是一个美丽的秋天
on another beautiful fall day here in paradise.
我们掌握了足够的情报
We have enough information.
我们可以回去了
We are returning home.
你想过我们是否会被卷入战争?
Do you ever wonder... if this war's gonna catch up with us?
没怎么想过
Not a whole lot.
我们没在一起的时候  为准备战争
Every moment we're not together,
你都在天上训练
you're up there training for it.
对  我还为现在这种情况接受过训练...
Yeah, well, I'm training for moments like these...
因为我根本不知道
'cause I have no idea...
如何把车子从沙坑里面开出来
how I'm gonna get this car out of the sand.
伊芙琳  你可以从浴室里面出来吗?
Evelyn, can you please come out of the bathroom?
你都进去一个小时啦
You've been there for an hour.
伊芙琳! 你干什么呢  想学我?
Evelyn! What are you trying to do, look like me?
你不舒服?
Are you OK?
没事
Yeah.
怎么了? 该死
What's the matter? No, you... D'oy.
他们称这为空海
They call it the vacant sea.
没有航道经过
None of the major sea lanes go through it...
你可以把整个亚洲藏在那儿
and you can bury the entire land mass of Asia there...
没人会知道
and nobody would know.
日本人可以从那儿向任何目标发起攻击
From there, they could attack anywhere.
最新的情报显示
Our last signals intercept indicate that the Japanese
日本的战斗编队正在向南行驶
taskforce is heading south...
到菲律宾或东南亚
towards the Philippines or southeast Asia.
但海军情报局的瑟曼上校对
But Captain Thurman of Naval intelligence
失踪的日本舰队有他自己的看法
here has his own theory about the missing ships.
长官  我认为
Sir, I believe they'll try to hit us where
他们要攻击我们的珍珠港
it'll hurt us the most... Pearl Harbor.
可这儿距离日本有四千海里远
It's over 4,000 nautical miles from Japan to Pearl.
舰艇编队跑不了这么远  上校
That's along distance to steam a navy, Captain.
你的根据是什么?
Your theory is based on what?
如果是我  我就会那样做
Well, it's what I would do.
但缺乏有说服力的证据  瑟曼上校
That's not exactly hard evidence, Captain Thurman.
嗯  将军  我有确切的证据时候  我们已经处于战争状态了
Well, Admiral, if I had hard evidence... we'd already be at war.
长官  我们可以很轻松地破译日本的外交密电
Sir, we can read their diplomatic codes faster than they can type them.
但瑟曼上校的破译小组还在研究日本海军的密码
But Captain Thurman's cryptology team is still trying to crack the naval codes.
截获的密电都缺行少字
The intercepts have missing words and garbled lines...
必须弄清楚他们的真实企图
so to explain the decrypts, we have to try to interpret
才有可能破译这些密电
what we think they're trying to do.
企图?你是说猜测
Interpret? You mean guess.
他们依靠自己的情报直觉  长官
They use their informed intuition, sir.
我们就像在黑暗中摸索  必须掌握一切
We guess. It's like playing chess in the dark.
每一个谣传、风吹草动
Any rumor, troop movement, ship movement spine- tingle,
或军队调动都要注意
goose bump, we pay attention to it.
我在驻守亚洲的时候
When I was in the
当地人会
Asiatic Fleet the locals used to try
从别的角度看问题
to get outside of a problem to try to see the inside.
偷袭珍珠港对美国是最致命的打击
Well, I see a strike on Pearl. It's the worst thing that could happen.
可以摧毁太平洋舰队的战斗力
A blow to Pearl would devastate the Pacific Fleet's ability to make war.
你要我们根据你的直觉
So, sir, you would have us mobilize the entire fleet...
花费数百万元让整个舰队进入战斗部署
at the cost of millions of dollars...
而根据就是你的风声鹤唳
based on this spine- tingling feeling of yours?
不是  长官  我的工作是收集情报
No, sir. My job is to gather and interpret material.
根据我破解的不完整情报
Making difficult decisions based on incomplete information...
做出困难的决定是您的责任  长官
...from my limited decoding ability is your job, sir.
那就快点破译这该死的密码  上校
Then break the damn naval code, Captain
这样我才能做出正确的决定
so I can make a better decision.
是的  长官  我们尽力
Aye, sir. We are trying.
我想知道我们是否应该让太平洋舰队进入全面警戒
I wonder if we shouldn't put the Pacific Fleet on full alert.
先生们  如果
In case the optimism of the
和谈结果并不乐观
"Honolulu Advertiser" proves unfounded, gentlemen...
肖特将军和陆军
what are General Short and the
能为我的舰队提供保护吗?
Army going to do about protecting my ships?
珍珠港半径十英里内
Within a ten- mile radius of your harbor,
惠勒机场有战斗机
we have fighter planes here at Wheeler...
希凯姆机场有轰炸机和训练用跑道
bombers at Hickam, and a training strip at Haleiwa.
左十度
我们最近在这新建了一个雷达站
We've recently established a radar station here
能侦察一百二十五英里外的敌机
that can detect planes 125 miles out.
那是一个月前才建成的  还没有检测过
Which is a month old, Admiral, and untested.
我也见过这些新雷达  少校
I've seen these new radar screens, Major.
它们根本分辨不出
There's no way of telling whether they're ours,
是敌机还是该死的鸟
theirs or a flock of damn birds.
(一九四一年十二月五日  珍珠港)
我监听到一个来自东京打到珍珠港附近某地的电话
I'm intercepting a call from Tokyo to somewhere close by Pearl.
东京来的  他说不认识你
There's a call from Tokyo. They say they don't know you.
你好?是我  喂  喂
Hello? Hai. Moshi, moshi
是个当地牙医  他说从他的办公室可以看到珍珠港
It's a local dentist. He can see Pearl Harbor from his office.
对方问有很多水手吗?
Are there many sailors around?
牙医说航空母舰没在港口
Uh, the dentist says that the flatships are not in port.
他们在谈天气
They're talking about the weather.
他好像不知道对方是谁
He doesn't seem to know who he's talking to.
喂?你好  喂? 莫名其妙
Hello? Moshi moshi. Hello? That was a strange call.
将军  能单独向您汇报吗?
Admiral, may I speak to you in private?
间谍为什么敢用电话? 他们知道我们在进行监听
Why would a spy use a phone? They know we tap all international lines.
监听人员认为他们并没有使用暗语
Our listeners feel it's probably not code talk.
听起来好像日本人想从本地居民口中
It sounds like someone in Japan is sneaking
打探我们的航空母舰在哪
around asking a local citizen the location of our carriers.
这让我觉得心里很乱  马上通知联邦调查局
Well, that makes me feel all warm inside. Get the FBI on it immediately.
我们还没找到那该死的日本舰队吗?
Have we found the goddamn Japanese Fleet yet?
还没有  将军  我们正在整个太平洋上搜索
No, Admiral. The bases are looking all over the Pacific.
那是不是该死的日本舰队在钻石海峡转悠
So the entire fleet could be rounding Diamond Head
所以我们才一无所知
and we wouldn't know a thing about it.
继续寻找
Get on it.
我还活着
I'm alive.
太困难了  我们没办法通知你
This is the first I could get word out.
(法语)
我答应过你一定会回来
I told you I'd come back.
来  坐吧  都过去了  没事了
Here, sit down. Sit down. Come here. It's OK. It's all right.
真的是你
You're real.
是啊
Yeah.
我每天都梦想这一天
I wished for this every day.
我也是  我每分每秒都在想你
I know. Me, too. Every second. So did I.
我以为你死了  他们说你被击落  掉进了海里
I thought you were dead. They said you were shot down in the sea.
没错
Yeah, I was.
我掉进海里  冷极了  我好想你
I was in the ocean. It was so cold. I missed you.
后来  法国渔船救起了我
I got picked up by a French fishing boat...
在法国的被占区  我不能写信给你
and I was in occupied France, and I couldn't get word out.
我差一点就  我会全部告诉你的  我保证
And I'm just... I'll tell you all about it, I promise.
现在好啦  我回来了
But I'm fine. I'm OK. And I'm here now.
伊芙琳  我好想见到你  你太美啦
Evelyn... I just wanted to see you. You're so beautiful.
我爱你
I love you.
嘿  都过去了  伊芙琳  我回来了
Hey, it's OK. It's OK. Evelyn, Evelyn. I'm back.
没事了  我发誓永远也不离开你了
It's OK. I won't leave you again, I promise.
雷夫  你死了
Rafe, you died.
我的心也死了
And so did I.
我知道  我现在回来了
I know, but I'm... I'm... It's fine now. I'm back.
我们团聚了
We're together.
我们又团聚了  对吧?
I mean, we are together... right?
我不知道我在哪
I don't know where I am.
雷夫
Rafe.
离我远点
Stay away.
雷夫
Rafe.
这里是檀香山电台
This is Radio Honolulu...
在这个令人愉快的太平洋岛屿上
playing the sweetest music on the sweetest island
在这个阳光明媚的十二月六日
in the Pacific.
我们为你送上优美的音乐
It's a beautiful December 6th with beautiful music
要是美国人起了疑心
他们的广播会告诉我们
雷夫
Rafe!
噢  我的妈呀
Oh, God damn it.
真正的王牌飞行员!
There you go. A real live ace!
王牌飞行员才击落了五架敌机  而我击落了六架
Whoo! An ace is only five. I shot down six M.E.s.
还有两架打冒了烟  他们没算进去
And I got two smokers, too. They don't count them.
我还没有受勋  就被打下来
Of course, I got shot down myself before they could pin me.
那你从前线回来了
So you got back from behind enemy lines, huh?
打仗到底是什么感觉?
What's that combat like?
你害怕吗?
Were you scared?
嗨!一个一个来
Hey! One at a time.
纳粹空军的技术非常棒
Well, them Luftwaffe boys can fly pretty good.
你要知道  这跟训练可是两码事儿  他们
It's not like, you know, training. They're, uh...
丹尼  知道吗  他们很讲究战术
Danny. You know, they're all about tactics is what it is.
纳粹飞行员比你飞得快
See, the Nazis, right, they're faster than you are...
他们钻进云层  一个俯冲
so they'll disappear and they get up in
就到你头顶
the soup and they'll throw like a roll or a hammerhead...
然后像某些美国人一样
and they'll come around on your high side
从背后偷袭你
shoot you from behind like some Americans will.
古斯  这才是真正的王牌
Hey... Gooz, you're looking at a real live ace.
让我把这件衬衫脱下来送给你!
Well, let me give you the shirt off my back!
拿去吧
There you go!
那我就不客气了
I'll take it from you.
反正我也需要便服
I can see how you all been spending your time out here.
嘿  雷夫  我们得谈谈  好吗?
Hey, Rafe, we gotta talk, all right?
我和你没什么好谈的  过来
I got nothing to talk about with you. Here.
干一杯吧
Why don't you have a drink?
我来敬酒
I'll make a toast.
为了死里逃生
To returning from the dead.
真没想到  可这就是生活
Wasn't all I expected, but, well, that's life.
敬我最好的朋友  丹尼
To my best friend and loyal buddy Danny...
为了他所做的一切干杯
for keeping up the war effort back here at home.
知道吗  在英国有人向你敬酒你却不喝
You know, where I come from somebody makes a toast to you...
那就是不给别人面子
...and you don't drink that's saying something.
好吧  雷夫  既然话都说到这个份上
All right, Rafe. That's how it's gonna be
为你干杯!
To you.
我想  你们两个需要单独谈谈
Hey, you guys need to spend some time alone, I think.
不  别走  雷德
Aw, hell, no, Red. Come on.
不  不  我们就在这儿庆祝
No, no, no. We're celebrating here.
我在前方打仗  差点送了命
Me over there fighting... almost getting killed...
我的朋友丹尼在后方  照顾我的一切
my friend Danny back here... looking after my interests for me.
你知道吗  他太好了
You all know Danny was even good enough
好得连我的女朋友都给照顾了
to look out for my girl for me while I was gone?
我们以为你阵亡了  雷夫  我们都很悲痛
We thought you were dead, Rafe. And it gutted us both.
可我们总还要继续生活下去
And we were just trying to get on with our lives.
你过得不错  对吧?
Life is good, ain't it, Danny?
你这个烂酒鬼  不讲道理  一直都是这样
You know, you're a rotten drunk. You always have been.
你这个卑鄙的朋友  我才发现
Well, you're a lousy friend. That's a new development.
你扔下她为别人去打仗
You left her to fight somebody else's war...
你还设法不让我去
and you made damn sure that
我们真的以为你死啦!
I didn't go with you and we thought that you were dead
我是差点就死了  你这个狗娘养的
I almost did die, you little son of a bitch!
那时候我想到的只有她
And her face was the last thing that went through my mind...
别站在那告诉我这一切都是理所当然的!
so don't stand there and tell me to act like it's all right!
不错  雷夫  我是留下了
Yeah, Rafe, well, I stayed.
你得知道情况改变了
I stayed, and you made sure of that and
我希望你能接受现实
some things changed. And I hope you can get used to that.
噢  我要接受现实? 好  让你看看我怎样接受的
Oh, I have to get used to it? All right. We'll see how I can get used to it.
接受我的拳头吧  小子!
Get used to that, boy!
我只用左手就够了
Hey, hey! And that's my left hand, too!
有人在打架  快派宪兵来!
Melee at the Hula- la. Send M.P. s!
你说我是卑鄙的朋友?
You called me a lousy friend?
可恶  来啊  丹尼!
Ow! Shit! Come on, Danny!
- 逮捕他们! - 快跑啊!
- Let's go get them. - Let's move out!
我们会被关禁闭的  快走!
They're gonna throw us in the brig. Let's get outta here.
编队在珍珠港北三百二十海里处待命
帝国的兴衰在此一役！
雷夫  你是我唯一的亲人
Rafe... you're the only family I got.
你不在的时候  我孤独极了
When you were gone it was the loneliest I'd ever been.
她和我一样
The same for her, too.
噢  小子  你现在真的是让我心都碎了
Oh, boy, now you're really breaking my heart.
你要是没走  什么都不会发生
If you hadn't gone, none of this woulda happened.
这么说我猜是我错了?
Oh, so it's my fault, I guess.
算了吧  雷夫
Damn it, Rafe.
我看我们总会有办法
I just know there's got to be some way...
妥善解决这个问题  让我们和好如初
we can work things out so that... things could be right between me and you.
我看永远也不可能了
I just don't see how it could ever be the same.
尊敬的父亲
Revered father...
现在我要去执行任务  完成我的使命
I go now to full- fill my mission and my destiny.
我希望能为我们全家带来荣誉
I hope it is a destiny that will bring honor to our family...
如果需要付出生命
and if it reguires my life,
我将在所不辞  精忠报国
I will sacrifice it gladly to be a good servant of our nation.
嘿  我看到一大片阴影
Hey... we got a large haze.
太大了不象飞机  对吧?
That's too big to be planes, right?
你想走这步? 要跳马?
Is that what you wanna do? Knight to knight five?
臭棋!
Wrong move.
长官! 雷达显示东北部有大量回波
Lieutenant, radar's picking up a large return moving in from the northeast.
等一下
Hang on.
别紧张
Relax.
那是从本土回来的 B- 17 轰炸机
It's a flight of B- 17s coming in from the mainland.
没什么可担心的
Nothing to worry about.
是一大群 B- 17 轰炸机
A heck of a lot of B- 17s.
打得好
Good shot, Hop.
这次有好点的消息了吧
This better be good, Commander.
我们的驱逐舰击沉了一艘日本潜艇
One of our destroyers reports having fired and sunk...
该潜艇于六时五十三分企图闯入珍珠港
enemy submarine attempting to enter Pearl Harbor at 0653.
现在七时二十分了
It's 7:20!
译电耽误了  将军
We had decoder delays, Admiral.
马上报告华盛顿  立即召集全部参谋人员
Relay this to Washington. Recall the staff.
和谈  失败  "终止谈判"
"Failure..."Peace talks..."useless."
我是瑟曼
Thurman here.
东京指示驻华盛顿使馆
Tokyo transmitting to their embassy in Washington
"立即破坏译码机"
"Discontinue use of your decoding machine...
"销毁秘密文件"
"and dispose of immediately. "Special emphasis on destroying important parts."
你看到了吗?
Do you read that?
将军  海军情报局截获了东京
Admiral... Naval Intel intercepted a transmission from Tokyo...
发给华盛顿日本使馆的电报
...to the Japanese embassy in Washington...
指示他们拆毁译码机
...instructing them to break apart all decoder machines
烧掉全部秘密文件
and burn all secret documents.
日本人要开战了
The Japanese are expecting a war.
我们是不是也该
Should we?
可以进行偷袭了
警惕日本人可能从任何方向发起的进攻
Warning of possible Japanese aggressive movement in any direction.
"中断关系  开始战争"
"Broken relationship. Hostilities imminent."
战争会在哪儿开始?
But where?
你曾经打输过吗  米勒?
Did you ever lose a fight, Miller?
很走运  还没有  舰长
I been lucky so far, Captain.
据我所知  这不仅仅是运气
From what I hear, it ain't luck.
你是我们军舰的骄傲
Ship's proud of you, son.
星期天海军这么早就搞飞行训练吗?
Why the hell's the Navy doing practice this early on a Sunday?
什么?
Aah!
快走  快走
Get down! Go, go, go, go!
我是海军新闻记者  我可以确定  海军没这种飞机!
I'm with Navy news reel, and I can tell you one thing... them ain't Navy planes!
我们遭到轰炸! 我们遭到轰炸! 快起来! 快起来!
We're being bombed! We're being bombed! Get up! Get up!
老天爷
Jesus Christ!
(亚利桑纳号)
所有人员进入战斗位置
Man your battle stations.
又是演习
Another dumb drill.
这是什么鬼东西?
What the heck was that?
是炸弹!
It's a bomb!
快走  快走  快走!
Move, move, move!
狗日的
Son of a bi...
给我接轮机舱
Get me the engine room!
天啊
My God.
汇报战斗状况! 所有人员进入战斗位置!
Report battle stations! Manned and ready! Man your battle stations!
这是来真的! 亚利桑纳被击沉了!
This is no shit! They just sunk the Arizona!
全面警戒!全面警戒!
Generalguarters! Generalguarters!
所有人员进入战斗位置!这不是演习!
All hands, man your battle stations! This is no damn drill!
快!快!
Go! Go!
好像是日本飞机
They look like Japs.
我不明白日本人为什么会恨我们
I didn't even know the Japs were sore at us!
丹尼  我他妈要有架飞机就好了!
Danny, you just get me to a goddamn airplane!
我的老天爷! 好精采的片段  看到了吗?
Holy God! This is good footage. Did you see that?
我的妈呀
Holy cow!
希望机场还没被炸掉
I hope there's still an airfield left.
大家快赶去医院
Everybody to the hospital!
海军的飞机在干什么?
Why's the Navy always buzzing us?
雷德  闭嘴!
Shut up, Red!
雷德  现在还早啊
Red, it's too early.
日本鬼子来了
The Japs are here!
什么鬼玩意儿?
What the hell?
快跑!快跑!
Let's go! Let's go!
叫医务员上舰桥来
Get corpsmen to the bridge.
是  舰长
Aye, Captain!
舰长  第三甲板左侧被淹没了
Repair says third deck is flooding portside!
起来  胆小鬼!快去战斗!快去!
Get up! Get up, you cowards! Get up there and fight! Move it!
我来了  舰长
I got you, Captain.
用无线电请求空中支援!
You radio for air cover!
开始伤患抑制!
Initiate damage control!
找到我的 X.O.  叫副舰长负责指挥  确保炮手
Find my X.O. Tell him to assume command. And you make sure the gunners...
舰长  所有人都已就位  你把我们训练得很好
Everyone's where they need to be, Captain. You trained us well. You trained us well.
舰长?
Captain...
走  快走!
Go, go, go, go! Let's go!
快走!大家快逃啊!
Let's go! Everybody move!
去拿机枪子弹!去拿子弹!
Get the ammo for that fifty cal! Get that fifty cal!
快跑
Let's go!
快点!快点把子弹装好!
We gotta get... Come on, man, we gotta get this thing loaded up!
啊!啊!来吧!
Aah! Aah! Let's go!
我们走!快点!我们走!
Let's go! Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
丹尼  他妈的快找架战斗机给我
Danny, get me into a damn plane!
快啊
Come on!
快去拿子弹来!我需要支援!
Get some ammo up here! We need some men on these guns!
长官!舰长说让您负责指挥!
Sir! The captain says you're in charge, sir!
我们现在需要弹药  马上  机枪需要弹药
We need more ammo! Now! Send up a munition for the five- inch guns!
来呀!混帐东西!
Come on! Aah! Come on! Come on, you sum' bitch!
好耶
Oh, yeah!
我需要医生  来人帮帮我!
I need a doctor! Somebody help me!
快去补给室
Get to the supply room!
把所有东西都搬出来!
Get everything out!
敌机来袭!
Planes incoming!
把吊架放下来
Cut them down!
快点  快点!把他们从窗前抬开!
Come on, come on! Get them away from the windows!
床垫!把它们靠在墙上!
The mattresses! Get them against the wall!
别开枪!去拿枪!快点!
Hold your fire! Get to the gun! Hurry up!
趴下来  丹尼!
Get down, Danny! Aah!
我是厄尔!
Earl.
我是沃克! 快给飞架加油、装子弹  马上!
This is Walker! We need to get those planes fueled and loaded right now!
外面到底是怎么回事?
What's going on out there?
丹尼  那是什么声音?
Danny, what the hell's that noise?
你们在搞射击训练还是其它鬼东西?
You guys doing target practice or something?
我看是二战爆发了
I think World War II just started.
比利  快跑
Go, go, go! Billy! Run!
是哑弹  是哑弹
It's gonna blow! It's a dud. It's a dud!
趴下来
Come on, get down!
丹尼  你没事吧?
Danny! Danny, are you all right?
- 没事!快走! - 古斯!大家快走!
- I'm all right! Come on, let's go! Come on, let's go!  - Gooz, come on, man!
我们要沉了!我们要沉了!
We're sinking! We're sinking!
靠在一起  关闭舱门
Stay together! Close the hatches!
我不会游泳!
I can't swim!
抓住缆索!
Just hang on!
乔  快走啊!
Let's move it now! Joe!
快!快!我们快离开这!快上车!
Go! Go! We're getting outta here! Get in the car!
上车!上车!来  我们走吧!
Get in! Get in! Come on, let's go! Go!
让开!让开!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
我们去哪儿?
Where's this place we're going?
大约开十分钟  会有一条小跑道  我们到那去
We got a small mechanic runway about ten minutes away.
它还没被炸掉
Hasn't been hit yet.
六点钟方向有有零式敌机!
We got Zeros on our six!
小心!
Duck!
帮帮我们!我们被困住了
Help us! Aah! We're trapped.
打开舱盖!打开舱盖!
Try it! Try the door!
我要被吞下去了!
It's sucking me back!
漩涡太大了!
The current's too strong!
他们还在还向我们扫射!
They're shooting at us!
我不想死!我不想死!
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
我们死定了
This is it.
情况有多糟?
How bad?
空袭还在继续  长官
It's still not over, sir.
整个舰队毫无戒备
An entire fleet at anchor.
我的上帝  我的上帝啊
My God, my God...
巴巴拉  把所有找到的注射器都装入吗啡
Barbara, fill every syringe you can find with morphine!
把伤员安置到厨房!你听到了吗?安置到厨房!
Fill up the kitchen! Are you listening to me? Fill up the kitchen!
厨房那儿!厨房那儿!
Over there! Over there!
他颈部受伤了!
We got a bad neck wound here!
手术室!快点!马上给他做手术!
Surgery! Move! Get him to surgery!
天哪! 来这儿!
Oh, God. In here!
他还在流血!给我止血钳
He's still bleeding! Another hemostat!
快点!我要止血钳和缝线  见鬼  快点!
Hurry! Give me a hemostat now! Damn it, hurry!
我还要止血钳和缝线  快点!
Give me another hemostat! Another suture! Hurry!
天哪! 很抱歉!
Oh, God, I'm so sorry!
医生
Doctor!
啊!我快死了吗?护士
Aah! Am I gonna die? Nurse!
别丢下我
Don't leave me!
医生  快来!
Doctor! Get over here!
我用手掐住了他的动脉
My fingers are plugging his artery!
医生  你需要什么?
Doctor, what do you need?
冷静点  看着我  你需要什么?
Focus, look at me. What do you need?
快走  走  走!
Move! Move! Go, go, go!
零式飞机!
Zeros!
快找掩体!
Take cover!
快找掩体!快找掩体!快找掩体!
Take cover! Take cover! Take cover!
趴下来!趴下来!我们走!
Get down! Get down! Let's go! In the box! Aah!
丹尼
Danny!
跟我来  兄弟!
Come on! Come on, buddy!
别管他  他死了!他已经死了!
Leave him, he's dead! He's dead!
他们不会放过我们  快到飞机那去!
They're kicking our butt. Get to the airplanes!
快  快
Go, go, go!
快跑!雷德  安东尼  我们走!
Run! Red, Anthony, let's go!
过来  帮帮我
Come on, help me!
该死的带子
Goddamn belts!
让他们好好瞧瞧
Knock them dead.
他们绕回来了  快走
Quick! Get in! Put this on! They're coming around.
雷德  让开!我要起飞
Red, get out of here, God damn it! Go!
快点
Come on, let's go.
乔  快开走
Joe, get out the way!
我马上离开
I'm rolling!
安全!起飞!
Clear! Go!
敌机!
Planes!
快来  帮帮我!
Come on, help me!
乔  有三架敌机在你后面  注意!
Hey, Joe! You got three Zeros behind you!
转向!转向!
Turn! Turn!
哎呀!糟糕!
Oh, God! Aah!
该死
Oh, shit.
动作快点  马上起飞
What are you doing? Get going!
丹尼  该我们开始进行空中表演了
Danny, start that thing up and get in the air.
没有僚机我可不行  我需要你!
I'm not much good without a wing man. I need you!
好的  收到!
I got you!
我们上!
Let's do it!
跑道太短了  雷夫
It's real tight, Rafe! Real tight!
嘿  雷夫  我们会撞上建筑物的
Hey, Rafe, I'm not sure we have enough runway!
起飞前开足马力
Get your airspeed up before you leave the dirt!
别紧张  别紧张
Don't freeze. Don't freeze.
我可能飞不过去
I don't think I'm gonna make it over!
我们成功了  飞起来了!
We did it! I'm up!
有敌机跟在我们后面
We got Zeros behind us!
你看到有几架?
How many you see back there?
六点钟方向有五架
We got five on our six!
超低空飞行  丹尼
Take it down to the deck, now!
要分散他们
We gotta split them up.
你往左、我往右
You take left, I'll take right.
厄尔  拿机枪到指挥塔
Earl, get some guns in that goddamn tower!
好  快走  去开卡车
OK! Let's go! Into the truck!
六点钟方向有三架敌机
Danny, I got three on my six.
停车  我们上指挥塔
Stop! Stop! Let's go!
走吧  快点  雷德
Let's go! Move it! Move it, Red!
快!快!
Go! Go!
仍有两架敌机缠着我  雷夫
I still got two behind me, Rafe.
婊子养的!
Son of a bitch!
厄尔!听到了吗? 妈的  快拿机枪上塔顶
Earl, do you hera me. God damn it, get some guns in that tower!
我正在上  塔可不低! 这儿有十层楼高
On the tower. Going ten stories up. It's a long son of a bitch.
雷夫  他们紧咬着我不放  我甩不掉
Rafe, they're all over me! I can't get them off me!
丹尼  我身后也有三架
Danny, I still got three on my tail!
颠簸飞行  别被他们盯死
Keep jinking it! Don't let them get a handle!
我还是甩不掉他们
I can't shake them!
可恶
God damn it.
丹尼  我们和他们玩"老鹰捉小鸡"
Danny, let's play chicken with these Jap suckers!
听你的
I'm with you.
天啊
Jesus!
我冲向你了
I'm coming right at you!
别转向  听我指挥
Don't brake till I tell you. Hold on.
还不行
Not yet! Not yet!
来呀
Come on!
向左急转
Go left! Now!
他们撞上了!
We got them!
把机枪架到哪儿
Set up over there!
装上弹药
Come on, load it!
我们准备好了
We're on the tower.
有架敌机跟着我  我引它过来
I got one on my tail. I'll bring him right by you.
雷夫过来了
He's coming around!
让我们来把这个日本笨鸟干掉!
Let's get this Jap sucker!
先别开火  他来了
Hold your fire. Here he comes.
厄尔  我飞过来的时候  你们最好瞄准一点
You better be cocked and locked when I come by there!
别开火
Hold your fire!
开火
Fire!
干得好  伙计们! 打得漂亮  厄尔
Good shooting, boys! Nice shot, Earl!
我们去码头看看
Let's head over to battleship row!
收到
I'm with you!
我们再打几架玩玩
Let's go do some business.
我去将他击落
I'm going after them.
雷夫  我打下一架
Rafe! I got him!
P40 战斗机
P- 40's!
他们钻进云层了!婊子养的  你们别想逃走!
They're pulling into the clouds! We ain't gonna let these sons of bitches get home!
现在轮到你挨揍了
How do you like someone shooting back at you?
噢  我盯死你了
Oh, I'm on your ass now!
丹尼  我打掉一架!
Yeah! I got one!
来呀
Come on!
来啊
God, come on!
别想逃
Come on, stay in there!
你死定了  王八蛋
I got you, you son of a bitch!
报告源田大佐  战果辉煌
摧毁多艘战舰
出动飞机三百五十架  损失二十九架
第三攻击波准备完毕  将军
突袭的意义已经不存在了
取消第三波攻击
上将
谁教你的绝招?
Who taught you how tofly, Lieutenant?
是他
He did.
我需要给他截肢
I have to amputate here! I have to amputate!
你不会死的
You're not gonna die! I got you.
桑得拉  吗啡快用完了  给注射过吗啡的伤员做记号
Sandra, we're running out of morphine. Find some way to mark them...
这样我们才清楚谁已经注射过了
So we can keep track of who's got morphine already.
你是哪一艘战舰的?战舰编号?
Tell me about your ship. What ship are you from?
不行  谁有签字笔?
It's not marking. Have you got a marker?
用我的口红
Use my lipstick!
M 代表吗啡
Put "M" for morphine.
我要止血钳
We need a tourniquet!
止血钳
Tourniquet!
钳子呢?
Where are the clamps?
都用光了
There's nothing left!
给  用这个
Here, use this.
伊芙琳  伤员太多了  到外面去  把伤员分成两组
Evelyn! Go outside. There's too many to help. Sort them out.
只让有抢救希望的进来  你懂吗?
Only those that can be saved you bring in. You got that?
我办不到
I can't...
快去  我需要你帮助  快点!
No, please, I need you to do it! Go! Go!
没有记号的不能进去
Don't look at anyone without a mark!
退后  我叫你退后
I told you, stand back!
别让他们进来
Keep them outside!
在这儿等
Wait here.
别碰我   日本鬼子  把你的臭手拿开
Don't touch me, you Jap! Get your hands off me!
带到加护病房
Get him into critical. Get him off me.
加护病房  向前走!
Critical, frontward!
我伤得多重?
How bad am I?
亲爱的  你不会有事
You're gonna be just fine, sweetheart.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
你不会死的  我会帮你的
You're not gonna die. I've got your hand.
有足够的吗啡给他止疼吗? 他快不行了  给他注射吗啡
Do you have enough morphine to make him comfortable? He won't make it.
让重伤患排好队!给他吗啡  把他们带过去!
Line the critical up! Get him morphine. Take him over there!
把烧伤病人带到树下
Burn victims by the tree!
我刚发现她  好像已经死了
I just found her! I don't think she's breathing.
她死了  把她
No, she's dead. Take her...
噢  天啊
Oh, God.
- 你确定吗?再检查一次  - 她已经死了
- Are you sure, Ev? Check her again. - She's dead.
抱她过去
Take her over there!
你一定要确定清楚
But you've gotta be sure!
她死了  快回去工作  桑得拉
She's dead! Go back to work, Sandra.
我不知道该做什么
I don't know what to do!
上将  华盛顿的电报
Admiral? From Washington.
[日本人的攻击迫在眉睫]
"Attack by Japan considered imminent."
他们只晚了一个小时
They're only an hour late.
恭喜了
我只怕这样做会唤醒了在沉睡中的巨人
我们能做点儿什么?
How can we help?
我们需要血  来吧
We need blood. Come on.
孩子  你要保持信仰  记住耶稣基督的话
Remember, son, hold on to your faith.
今日你将随我进天堂
Today you will be with me in paradise...
不要恐惧  我的孩子
"so fear not." Fear not, my son.
你受到祝福  将蒙主荣召
You are a man truly blessed. You will die in a state of grace.
痛苦很短暂、荣耀是永恒的
Remember, pain is temporary, but glory is forever.
坚信主耶稣基督  很快便将与上帝与天使同在
Hold on to your faith, my son. You'll be with God, the saints, and the angels soon.
我赦免你犯下的过错  以圣父、圣子、圣灵之名
I absolve you of your sins... in the name of the Father, the Son, the Holy Spirit.
阿门
In nomine patris et fili, et spiritus sancti. Amen.
与上帝同在
Go with God, my son.
我们的人都困在码头
We've got men trapped everywhere in the harbor.
有力气搬得动东西的快来帮忙
We need help from anybody who can move.
救我们出去
There's somebody in here!
这儿有人  快派人下去
Get somebody down here! They're cutting through!
这儿也有人  快派人下去
I hear somebody! Get some guys uphere!
用力拉
Pull!
快救我们出去!水快满了!
Get us out! It's filling with water!
快拿输气管过来!
Get an airline in here!
我们该怎么做?
What can we do?
速度不能再快了
It won't cut any faster!
快把它钊开
Cut him out! Aah!
昨天  一九四一年十二月七日
Yesterday... December 7, 1941...
将永远成为我们的国耻日
a date which will live in infamy...
美利坚合众国遭到日本
the United States of America was suddenly and deliberately attacked...
海空军有预谋的突然袭击
by naval and air forces of the Empire of Japan.
显然易见  这次袭击是经过长期精心策划的
It is obvious that planning the attack began many weeks ago.
在此期间  日本政府
During the intervening time... the Japanese government...
通过虚伪的声明和维护和平的宣传
has deliberately sought to deceive the United States by false statements...
蓄意欺骗美国
and expressions of hope for continued peace.
昨天对夏威夷群岛的攻击
The attack yesterday on the Hawaiian Islands...
使美国军队遭受重创
has caused severe damage to American military forces.
我沉痛地告诉各位  有三千多美国人丧失了生命
I regret to tell you... that over 3,000 American lives have been lost.
无论需要多长时间也要战胜  敌人预谋的侵略
No matter how long it may take us... to overcome this premeditated invasion...
正义的美国人民  必将赢得彻底的胜利
the American people, in their righteous might... will win through to absolute victory.
由于日本无故发动的卑鄙袭击
Because of this unprovoked, dastardly attack by Japan...
我要求国会宣布进入战争状态
I ask that the Congress declare a state of war.
是不是还有士兵被困在亚里桑那号里
Is it true... men are still trapped alive inside the Arizona?
舰内传来敲打声
We can heartapping from inside the hull.
我们正在尽力抢救  但他们被困在四十尺海底
We're doing everything we can to get to them... but they're forty feet below water.
美国人自以为所向无敌
We've been trained to think that we're invincible.
可我们最值得骄傲的战舰
And now our proudest ships have been destroyed...
却被我们藐视的敌人击沉了
by an enemy we considered inferior.
我们被逼得无路可退  所以一定要马上反击
We're on the ropes, gentlemen. That's exactly why we have to strike back now.
我们准备攻击马绍尔和吉尔伯特群岛
We'll attack the Marshall and Gilbert Islands, sir.
我的意思是要攻击日本的心脏  就象他们攻击我们一样
I mean hitting the heart of Japan the way they have hit us.
总统先生  珍珠港遭袭击是缺乏准备造成的
Mr. President... Pearl Harbor caught us unawares because we didn't face facts.
不过我们应该面对现实
This isn't a time for ignoring them again.
我们有远程轰炸机  但在日本附近没有基地
We have long- range bombers, but no place to launch them.
中途岛离日本太远  苏联也不会帮助我们
Midway is too far, and Russia won't allow us... to launch a raid from there.
海军上将?
Admiral?
海军航空兵都是轻型飞机  载弹量低、航程短
Navy's planes are small. They carry light loads and have a short range.
只能够从距离日本几百英里的地方起飞才能够进行轰炸
We'd have to get them within a few hundred miles of Japan.
这样的话  就必须动用航母  但是  如果我们失去航母
We'd risk our carriers, and if we lose our carriers...
我们将丧失抵御入侵的能力
...we'll have no shield against invasion.
有人见过不流血的胜利吗?
Does anyone in this room think victory is possible without facing danger?
要进行战争  就必然有危险
We are at war. Of course there's a risk.
但我们不能无视危险  总统先生  如果日本人继续进攻
But consider the risk, Mr. President. If the Japanese invade us right now...
在我们能够挡住他们之前  他们可以打到芝加哥
they would reach Chicago before we could stop them.
先生们
Gentlemen...
在我双腿残疾之前  你们大多数人还不认识我
most of you did not know me when I had the use of my legs.
那时  我强壮  充满自信
I was strong and proud... and arrogant.
现在我时时刻刻在问自己  为什么上帝让我做在轮椅上?
Now I wonder, every hour of my life... why God put me into this chair.
国民流露出失败的情绪
But when I see defeat in the eyes of my countrymen...
而你们也是如此
in your eyes, right now...
我开始认为上帝
I start to think that maybe he brought me down...
就是让我来
for times like these...
提醒大家我们到底是谁
when we all need to be reminded who we truly are...
我们永不放弃  决不低头!
that we will not give up or give in.
尊敬的总统先生  恕我直言
Mr. President, with all respect, sir...
您的要求是不可能办到的
what you're asking can't be done.
总统先生
Mr. President!
别扶我  乔治  别扶我
Get back, George! Get back.
别再告诉我  没有什么是不可能!
Do not tell me... it can't be done.
日本继续在南太平洋炫耀武力
Japan continues its military conguest... throughout the Pacific.
在国内  美国的自愿者在加紧工作
But, backhome... millions of American workers band together...
为雪十二月七日之耻 努力生产武器
bringing factories to life to avenge Pearl Harbor.
总统先生  我们制定了轰炸东京的计划
Mr. President, we have an idea how to bomb the Japanese.
很危险  但很大胆
Sir, it's risky... but it's bold.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我吗?
I, sir?
我是洛上校  总统先生
Captain Low, Mr. President.
是他拟制的计划  它是潜艇舰长
He's a submariner. He came up with this idea.
我喜欢潜艇舰长
I like sub commanders.
他们没时间讲废话  我也一样
They don't have time for bullshit, and neither do I.
开始吧  先生们
Fire away, gentlemen.
上帝啊!你在哪里?
And where is God in all this?
我们的敌人认为神风在保护他们
Our enemies believe a divine wind protects them.
可我们的朋友却在此长眠
But we see our friends laid out there before us.
(西维吉尼亚号舰长)
别了  舰长
Hey, Captain.
雷夫・麦考利中尉、丹尼・沃克中尉
Lieutenants Rafe McCawley, Daniel Walker.
是的  少校
Yes, Major?
两小时后  你们回本土
You're both going stateside. Fly out in two hours.
什么事儿?长官
What for, sir?
去问杜立特上校
Ask Colonel Doolittle.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你们要出发
You're packing.
这是任务
Orders.
什么样的任务?
What kind of orders?
最高机密
The top- secret kind.
也是最危险的?
The dangerous kind.
我没看见丹尼
I can't find Danny.
那是你来这来的原因?
Is that why you're here?
来找丹尼?
Looking for Danny?
可能在和他的队友告别
Probably saying good- bye to his squadron.
我们现在归杜立特指挥
We've been assigned to Doolittle.
我不是来找丹尼的
I wasn't looking for Danny.
有一件事儿  在你走之前我想你应该知道
I couldn't have you go away without you understanding something.
是吗  你什么都不必解释
Yeah. You don't have to explain anything.
我要  因为你以为我没有爱过你
I do, because you're acting like I didn't love you.
伊芙琳  爱你使我活了下来
Evelyn, loving you kept me alive.
不然  在英国我早就死了
I should've died over there.
当我掉进海里的时候  我向上帝承诺
When I was in that water, I made a deal with God.
我说我后悔极了
I told him I was sorry...
为了当英雄  我离开了你
I told him that I knew I'd been a fool for leaving you
真是太傻了
trying to go over there and be a hero...
我向上帝承诺  从今后我别无所求
and I promised I'd never ask for anything again...
只要我能够再见你一面
...if I could just see you one more time.
你知道吗?
And you know what?
我觉得我值得这样做
It was worth it.
伊芙琳  是你让我活了下来  是你把我带回了家
You kept me alive, Evelyn. You brought me home.
所以我要实现我的承诺
So I'm gonna stand by my end of the deal.
我要走了  我对你别无所求
I'm gonna walk away. And I won't ask you for anything.
但是  我想知道为什么
But I just want to know why.
请告诉我  好吗?求你了  请告诉我
Just tell me that, will you, please? Just tell me why.
雷夫  我怀孕了
Rafe, I'm pregnant.
噢  老天
Oh, my God.
我也是你回来那天才知道的
I didn't even know until the day you turned up alive.
后来就发生了这些事情  我没有告诉丹尼
And then all this happened. I haven't told Danny.
我不想让他知道
I don't want him to know.
他现在需要考虑的是
All he needs to think about is how to do
如何完成任务活着回来
this mission and get back alive.
雷夫  我过去的全部心愿就是嫁给你
Rafe, all I ever wanted was for us to have a home,
和你一起慢慢变老
grow old together...
老天却不让我如愿以偿
but life never asked me what I wanted.
现在我要全心全意地爱丹尼
Now, I'm gonna give Danny my whole heart...
我曾经深深的爱着你
but I don't think I'll ever look at another
无时无刻想着你
sunset without thinking of you.
你是我生命中的最爱
I'll love you my whole life.
飞机上见
I'll see you on board.
知道吗  我唯一害怕的事情
You know, the only thing that scares me is
就是你对他的感情胜过我
that you might love him more than you love me.
我爱你  丹尼!
I love you, Danny.
我会在这等你  等你完成任务回来
And I'll be here waiting for you when you come back.
跟我来
Follow me.
上校
Colonel.
祝贺您晋升了  长官
Congratulations on your promotion, sir.
我听说你们的事情了
I heard what you did.
我们可以解释清楚  长官
We can explain that, sir.
解释什么?
Explain what?
不管你听说到的什么  长官
Whatever it is you heard about us, sir.
你是指你们穿着花衬衫开飞机?
You mean the hula shirts you were flying in?
还是你们击落的七架敌机?
Or the seven planes you shot down?
你们都能够获得银星勋章
You're both being awarded the Silver Star...
还要晋升上尉军衔
and promoted to captain.
就是这些好消息吗?长官  或
Is that the good news, sir, or...
在陆军飞行员之中
You're just about the only pilots in the Army
你们是唯一有实战经验的
with combat experience.
我需要你们完成一项任务
I need you for a mission I've been ordered to put together.
你们知道什么事最绝密吗?
You know what top secret is?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
就是你能够获得勋章
It's the kind of mission where you get medals.
但是他们只能颁发给你的家属
But they send them to your relatives.
最高绝密  就是说你们将为航空史
Top secret means you train for something
上绝无先例的任务接受训练
never done before in aviation history...
甚至连去哪儿都不能知道
and you go without knowing where you're going.
你们干还是不干
You do it on that basis or not at all.
我要去  长官
I'll go, sir.
我也去  长官
I'll go, too, sir.
另外  麦考利  英方送来了你的私人物品
By the way, the Brits sent over your personal effects.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
还有一件事我要告诉你们
There's only one more thing I can tell you.
把你们的花衬衫留在家里
Leave your goddamn hula shirts at home.
亲爱的雷夫
Dear Rafe...
没有你的日子我很不习惯
It's so strange to be this far from you...
但你应该每个这样的夜晚
but you should know this every night...
我到处找你
I've been looking all over for you.
丹尼  这
Danny, this...
现在这个时候我们最好开诚布公
this ain't no time to leave things unsaid.
我们要面对现实
Now, we got to face facts here.
现实就是  我们爱上同一个女人
The fact is, we just both love the same woman.
你知道她是我爱上的第一个女孩  雷夫
You know she's the first girl I ever felt this way about, Rafe.
我情不自禁  就跟你一样
I couldn't help what happened any more than you could.
可是这次不一样  丹尼
This is different, though, Danny.
伊芙琳曾经失去过一次爱人
Evelyn already lost the man she loved once.
我不想这样的事情再次发生在她身上
I just don't want it to see that happen to her again.
我们没有选择  这是战争
Guys like us got no choice. This is war.
她很清楚
She knows that.
丹尼  别这样
Danny, don't do this.
别参加这次任务
Don't go on this mission.
你不必证明什么
You got nothing to prove.
你从小就在保护我
You've been protecting me since we were kids.
对  没错
Yeah,well...
你这人是挺需要保护的
you do tend to need it from time to time.
(一九四二年三月三日)
我要求你们自愿参加的任务
The mission I'm asking you to volunteer for...
非常危险
is exceptionally dangerous.
看看你身边的同伴
Take a look at the man beside you.
很可能六个星期后
It's a good bet that in the next six weeks...
你  或者是他已经牺牲了
you or he... will be dead.
有足够勇气的  向前一步
Everyone brave enough to accept this... step forward.
你们的祖母可以驾驶 B- 25 在一英里的跑道上起飞
Your grandmother could take a B- 25 off... on a mile- long runway.
现在我要求你们在四百六十七英尺的跑道上起飞
Well, I'm gonna train you to do it in 467 feet.
因为超过了四百六十七英尺  你只有命丧黄泉
Because at 468 feet... you're dead.
起飞后  要象驾驶战斗机一样
And once you get it up you'll learn to fly it like a fighter...
距离地面三十英尺飞行
...thirty feet off the ground.
这位是海军航空兵的杰克・理查兹上尉
I want you to say hello to Lieutenant Jack Richards, Navy Aviation.
他将帮我们为这些胖妞减减肥
He'll help us lighten these fat ladies.
把那个箱子扔掉
Dump that ashcan. Dumpt hat ashcan.
看到瞄准镜了吗?卸掉
See that bomb sight? Get rid of it.
上校  他疯啦!
Colonel, he's crazy!
这位女士太肥了
The lady's fat!
听他指挥
Listen to him.
不要胖妞  我们要一位骨感美的美女
She's fat lady. We want a skinny lady!
开足马力
Max power!
拉起来  拉起来!
Get up, get up!
见鬼!
Damn!
他们超过了起飞线
They just keep rolling past that line.
也许是这个主意不好
Maybe it's a bad idea.
不  还是太重  得动大手术
No, they're too heavy. We gotta get drastic.
这些防弹板
This armored plating goes.
对  就是它  就像脱裙子一样卸掉  年轻人
I'm sure, I'm sure. Lose it like a skirt, son.
松开刹车
Release brakes!
快  快
Come on, come on!
让所有人都站过来
Put every man on the line now!
我们告诉他们怎么飞
Let's show these boys how this thing is done!
准备好!开足马力!
Come on! Max power.
看  如果他行
Well, if he can do it...
(一九四二年四月二日  大黄蜂号航空母舰)
先生们  现在我可以告诉你们  我们要去东京
Well, gentlemen, now I can tell you... that we're going to Tokyo.
去轰炸它
And we're gonna bomb it.
这是罗斯福总统直接特批的任务
That comes as a special request directly from President Roosevelt.
海军送我们到距日本本土四百海里的地方
The Navy'll sneak us about 400 miles off the Japanese coast...
然后我们从航母上起飞
and we'll launch from the carrier there.
以前曾经这么干过吗?
Has that been done before?
陆军轰炸机从海军航母上起飞?
Taking Army bombers off Navy carriers?
没有
No.
好吧
OK.
还有问题吗?
Any other questions?
嗯  长官  B- 25 能在航母甲板上降落吗?
Well, sir, is it even possible to land a B- 25 on an aircraft carrier deck?
不存在这个问题
That won't matter.
我们起飞后  航母马上返航回夏威夷
As soon as we're airborne, the carrier heads for Hawaii.
没有航母  那我们在哪儿降落?
But without them, where do we land?
我要你们都学会用中文说一句话
I have a phrase I want you to memorize.
我是一个美国人
Wo shi yi ge mei guo ren.
意思是"我是一个美国人"
It means 'I am an American'.
用中国话说
In Chinese.
这可不简单  甲板比我们训练的起飞距离
ain't gonna be any easier.
还短三英尺
That's three feet shorter than our practice runway.
两位
Fellas?
长官
Sir.
这是海军部长给的
Secretary of the Navy gave me these.
什么东西?
What are they?
日本人送的友谊勋章
Friendship medals the Japanese gave
那时候他们还在大谈和平
us when they were pretending to want peace.
我们拿它有什么用?
What'll you do with them?
系在炸弹上还给他们
Wire them to the bombs and give them back.
还有什么事?
So what's going on?
长官  我们只有十六架轰炸机
Well, sir, we only have sixteen planes.
那又怎样?
So?
如果日本人反击  他们能够出动三百多架
When the Japs hit us, they had more than 300.
力量对比太悬殊
How much difference can we make?
我们并不是害怕  我们可能会死
It's not that we're afraid, sir. But we might die,
但我们想知道这是为什么
and we want to know what it's for.
在珍珠港  他们疯狂地袭击了我们
You know, at Pearl, they hit us with a sledgehammer.
这次空袭  即使成功
This raid, even if we make it through...
也微不足道
it'll only be a pinprick...
但我们这是在直接打击他们的心脏
but it'll be straight through their hearts.
胜利属于那些信念坚定
Victory belongs to those that believe in it the most...
永不动摇的人们
and believe in it the longest.
我们坚信胜利  我们也要让美国人民坚信胜利
We're gonna believe. We're gonna make America believe, too.
上校  请来一下
Colonel? I need a minute.
对不起  杰克森少校
Excuse me, Major Jackson?
是
Yes?
你还记得我吗?
Do you remember me?
当然记得 我还没感谢你呢
Oh, sure I do. I'm sorry. I've been meaning to thank you.
你的机会来了
Well, maybe you can.
我想去指挥所听听
When the news comes in about the Doolittle boys
杜立特部下发回的消息
I want to be in the command post.
抱歉  我不知道你在说什么
I'm sorry. I don't know what you're talking about.
你怎么知道这项任务?
How the hell do you know about this mission?
算是不慎泄漏吧
Let's call it an inadvertent disclosure.
是某个和你约会的飞行员说的?
Some flyboy you're dating shot his mouth off.
实际上  是两名飞行员
Actually, it's about two pilots.
我知道他们面对巨大的危险
I know they're going into great danger.
我只想在那儿亲耳听到
I just want to be there
他们生还或是牺牲的消息
when the news tells us if they've lived or died.
要是其他军官早就把你扔进监狱了
Most officers would have thrown you in the brig.
要是别的护士早就顾不上你
Most nurses wouldn't keep their fingers plugged
没时间用手按住你流血的动脉
in your artery.
我不能保证什么
I can't promise you anything.
嘿  雷德
Hey, Red,
你以为他们选中我们是因为我们年轻  好说话吗?
you think they pickedus to do this bcause we're young and dumb?
拜托  古斯  因为我们是精英
Come on, Gooz, we're the tip of the sword.
(为了贝蒂)
为了我们的日本之行  我搞到一些胜利雪茄
In honor of our trip to Japan... I got us some victory cigars!
拿去吧  放在靠近心脏的步袋里
There you go. Put that in your inside pocket, next to your heart.
知道吗  杰克  这一仗可能会失败
You know, Jack, we may lose this battle...
但我们一定能赢得这场战争
but we're gonna win this war.
你明白我的意思吗?
You know how I know?
不知道
No.
他们  因为他们的杰出贡献
Them. bcause they're rare.
因为他们在这种关键时刻  自愿挺身而出
And at times like these, you see them... stepping forward.
自愿者的意志无坚不摧  杰克
There's nothing stronger than the heart of a volunteer, Jack.
我在作战部的朋友不想让我指挥这次空袭
My friends in the war department don't want me to lead this raid...
他们说我太宝贵了
because they say I'm too valuable.
他们不希望我跟我挑选的
They don't want me up in the air flying with the men
飞行员一起出任务
that I've chosen...
可他们是我挑选的  是我训练和逼出来的
that I've chewed out, cussed out, pushed to the limit...
我很尊重这些飞行员
and that I've come to respect.
他们想让我在甲板上发号施令
They want me to stand on the flightdeck and wave you off.
但我不想那样做
Well, I don't see it that way.
我要跟你们一起去
So I'm going with you.
我们明天下午起飞  轰炸完毕后去中国
We take off tomorrow afternoon... drop our fire, and head for China.
我们的任务是轰炸他们的军事目标  飞机工厂和坦克工厂
Our mission is to hit military targets... aircraft and tank factories.
上校  你说我们有返航引导信号
Colonel, you've given us homing beacons...
但你又说  中国到处是日本军队
but you said China is overrun with Japanese troops.
如果信号中断  怎么办?
What if the beacons are switched off?
那就紧急迫降并尽量避免被日本人抓住
Bring her down any way you can...and do your best to avoid capture.
如果必须在日本人的上空跳伞  我们该怎么办?
What if we have to bail out over Japan?
这种情况  我无可奉告
Well, in that situation, I can't tell you what to do.
你会怎么做  上校?
What would you do, Colonel?
我天生不会做俘虏
I wasn't built to be a prisoner...
所以我会先让机组跳伞
so I would have my crew bail out.
然后选择一个重要的军事目标驾机
I'd find the sweetest military target
与敌人同归于尽
I could and drive my plane right smack into the middle of it
但这仅限于我
But that's just me.
我是四十五岁的老家伙
I'm forty- five years old. I'm an old man.
而你们还有很长的路要走
You guys have your whole lives ahead of you...
一切由你们自己决定
so what you do is up to you.
再有几个小时就要开始行动了
The mission will launch in a couple of hours.
一九四二年四月十八日
你就待在这
You'll stay right in here.
这  待在这儿
Here. Stay here.
别和她们说话  她们也没空理你的
Don't talk to them. They won't talk to you.
假装打我们发给你的信息  就这样
Pretend to type the information we pass you. That's it.
这儿是东京广播电台 孤儿安妮开始播音
This is Orphan Annie from Radio Tokyo.
南太平洋上孤独的小伙子们
To all the lonely boys in the South Pacific...
小心  敌人会找上你
watch out... the enemy will get you.
也许她说的对
Maybe she's right.
日本人在发报!
Japs transmitting!
舰长  雷达发现距离四百码处有日本巡逻艇
Captain, radar reports Japanese patrol boats. Range 400 yards.
多远? 四百码  正在靠近  长官
How many yards? 400 yards and closing, sir.
理查兹  快  日军逼近  快走
Richards, Japs! 400 yards! Let's go!
哈尔西将军命令巡洋舰开火
Admiral Halsey's ordering the cruisers to open fire!
日本巡逻艇可能会报告我们的位置
We gotta sink these Jap boats before they give us away.
全体人员就位
Go to general quarters!
快  快
Go, go, go, go!
我的天
Oh, my God.
情况不妙
This can't be good!
日本人距离一海里  正在报告我们的位置
Japs one mile away. They reported our position.
预定起飞点在四百海里处  现在还有多远
Supposed to launch 400 miles away. How far are we now?
还有六百二十四海里
624 miles.
老天!你要怎么办?
Jesus! What do you want to do?
我不知道  上校
I don't know, Colonel,
我不知道我们的燃料能否飞到中国
I don't know if the planes can carry enough fuel to make it to China.
我们现在起飞
Now. We launch now!
陆军飞行员  立即就位!
Army pilots! Man your planes! Man your planes!
他们已经开火了!
They're shooting at something.
这不是演习  快走!
Let's go! It ain't a drill!
上校!距离太远飞机飞不过去!
Colonel! We're too far out to make it!
他们需要加更多的油  但油多了飞机又太重  起飞有困难
They need more fuel, but they can't get too heavy!
听着!卸下所有能卸的东西!马上去办!
Listen! Strip everything out of this plane you don't need now!
我要做飞行前检查!快!
Start pre- flight! Let's go!
每架飞机多带十桶油!所有飞机都是!
Add ten cans of fuel for each plane! Every plane!
动作快点
Let's go! Move!
伙计们  快上去
Guys, get up there!
快把皮箱丢掉
Lose those suitcases now!
- 还有你的宝贝机枪  - 什么?
- What's your favorite gun?  - What?
快卸下一挺机枪!马上!否则飞机太重了!
You want off this deck, give me a gun now! It's still too heavy!
你  去厨房找几根扫把
You, go to the kitchen, get some broomsticks.
把它们锯断  染黑后拿过来
Cut them down, paint them black, and bring them here.
- 把扫把放在机枪的位置上  - 你在对我的飞机干什么?
- We'll put a broomstick where this gun was. - What are you doing to my plane?
起飞前叫机组人员小便  减轻起飞重量
Tell your crew to take a piss before they take off.
我们的尾部机枪换成了扫把
We got broomsticks for tail guns.
是啊  能吓死日本人
Yeah. Maybe it'll scare them.
你要多保重
You take care of yourself up there.
没问题  我会的
Yeah, I will.
丹尼  要小心!听到了吗?
Danny, be careful, you hear me?
我会的  回头见  雷夫
I will, see you, Rafe.
雷夫!我们是精英
Rafe! We're the tip of the sword!
启动一号螺旋桨
Turning on one!
启动二号螺旋桨
Turning on two!
好了
All right.
你准备好了吗?
You ready for this?
增压舱压力低并关闭!
Super chargers low and latched!
压力低并关闭!
Low and latched.
我们要逆风航行
We're full into the wind!
加速航行!加速航行!
More speed! More speed!
你紧张吗?
Are you nervous?
不紧张  长官  是有点
No... yes, sir. Yes.
什么时候开始信教了?
When did you find religion?
在你选中我的时候  长官
When you assigned me to this mission, sir.
帮我个忙
I want you do me a favor.
什么忙?上校
What's that, Colonel?
替我们祷告
Pray for both of us.
走吧
Let's go!
开足马力!
Max power!
快点快点
Come on! Come on!
天啊  跑道太短了
Jesus, that was short.
快  快
Move them up!
全速前进  来吧
Full power, here we go!
来吧  来吧
Come on, here we go, here we go!
我们成功了!
We made it!
在柏林  罗马和东京
From Berlin, Rome, and Tokyo
有人说我们是懦夫和纨绔子弟的国家
we have been described as anation of weaklings and playboys...
只能雇佣英国、苏联或中国的士兵替我们打仗
who hire British, Russian, or Chinese soldiers... to do our fighting forus.
现在让他们再重复一遍
Let them repeat that now.
让他们向麦克阿瑟将军和他们的士兵们说吧
Let them tell that to General MacArthur and his men.
让他们对那些浴血奋战
Let them tell that to the soldiers who
在太平洋上的士兵们说吧
today are fighting hard in the far waters of the Pacific.
让他们对空中堡垒的勇士们说吧
Let them tell that to the boys in the flying fortresses.
让他们对海军陆战队的官兵说吧
Let them tell that to the Marines.
日本就在前面  伙计们  保持队形
That's Japan, fellas. Tighten up back there!
准备战斗
Man your guns!
我们到敌人的老家了
We're in the enemy's backyard!
准备就绪  我看到了海岸线
Look alive back there. I see coastline.
提高警戒!小伙子们  提高警戒!
Heads up, boys! Heads up!
一切准备完毕!
Man your guns back there.
机关枪上膛
I'm cocked and locked!
狗日的  等着挨炸吧
Get ready, suckers!
接近轰炸目标  准备投弹
Approaching targets for bombing raid! Open bomb bay doors.
看到目标吗?
Ripley, you gota target in sight?
三十七度!目标进入视野
37 degrees! Target in sight!
好了  小伙子们  让他们也尝尝挨炸的滋味!
All right, boys, let's knock their clocks off!
投弹!
Drop your ordnance!
投下炸弹!投下第一枚
Bombs away! One away!
投弹
Bombs away! Bombs away!
第二枚
Two away!
第三枚  第四枚
Three away! Four away!
我们让他们也吃一惊!投弹!
We caught them by surprise! Dropping ordnance!
连续投弹
Bombs away!
命中兵工厂
...factory.
我们成功了!我们命中目标!干得好!
We got it! We hit our targets! Good job, raiders!
到处都是敌人的高射炮火!
We got flak everywhere!
怎么回事?
Go down there and get Gooz!
我命令大家立即分散
I want everyone to separate!
- 赶快调整频率  - 是  长官  - 赶快调整频率!
- Clean that up! - Yes, sir. - Try and clean that up!
高射炮正在向我们射击!我们得快脱身  古斯!
They're shooting flak at us! We gotta get out of this shit, Gooz!
起火了
We got a fire!
机尾被击中!电器系统着火了!
Tail's hit! The electrics! We got a fire backhere!
我马上就把它扑灭
I gotta short this out!
飞进云层  丹尼!快!
Get into the clouds, Danny, right now!
可恶
God damn!
雷德  快去检查一下!
Red, go check that out!
到处都是炮火
We're getting covered!
希望螺旋桨别被打中!
Just hope they don't hit a prop!
我受伤了!
I'm hit!
飞机要被打烂了
They're tearing this plane apart!
雷德  快拉高到八百英尺
Red, take it up, 800 feet.
西欧好像死了
I think Theo's dead!
西欧  快醒醒  西欧
Theo, wake up! Theo!
快飞进云层  丹尼  要快!飞进云层!
Get into the clouds, Danny, right now! Get up in that soup!
马上离开这里  古斯
We're gonna pull out of this, Gooz!
谢谢你  乔治
Thank you, George.
有消息吗?将军
What is it, General?
杜立特上校不得不
Colonel Doolittle had to advance his
提前十二个小时起飞
execution order by twelve hours,
总统先生
Mr. President.
没有引导信号了
There will be no homing beacons.
导航机在中国坠毁
The plane carrying them crashed en route to China...
我们的轰炸机燃油不足  他们飞不到中国大陆
and our bombers may lack the fuel to reach the mainland, sir.
那他们等于是瞎了眼睛  空着油箱在飞行
So our boys are flying blind on empty tanks.
上帝保佑他们
God help them.
还是没收到信号
We're still not getting a signal.
一片汪洋  看不见有陆地  也没有信号
All ocean and no land. Homing in on nothing.
我们还剩几桶油?
How many cans of fuel we got left?
这些都空了
These are all empty!
只剩这桶吗?
Is this all you got?
对  只有这点了  雷德
That's all we got, Red.
雷夫  你最好祈祷陆地快些出现吧
Rafe! You better pray for land!
恢复无线电通话
Break radio silence.
很抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
你们非常勇敢
You're all brave souls.
是我见过的最英勇的飞行员
The bravest I've ever had the privilege of flying with.
但现在我们只能靠自己了
But we're on our own.
这真是一项自杀型的任务
This really was a suicide mission.
注意  一号引擎出现问题
Engine one's fluctuating.
它随时都会熄火
We'll lose it any minute.
雷夫  快给引擎加油
Rafe, you gotta prime it.
我正在加! 现在怎么样?
I am. How about now?
我看见海岸了  看见海岸了!
I see the coast. I see the coast!
收到  雷夫
Copy that, Rafe.
我们准备着陆
We're gonna make it.
丹尼  跟着我  我们要成功了
Danny, follow me. We can make this.
陆地就在前面  只有几英里远
I can see the coast now. We're only a few miles out.
跟着我
Follow me.
我们要找个土质松软的地方着陆
We gotta find a soft landing spot.
二号引擎加速
I'm pushing up on two.
我们马上迫降
Hold on for a hard landing!
我看到一片稻田  我们就迫降在那
I see rice paddies. We'll bring it in right here.
噢  天啊  一号引擎熄火了
Oh, God, engine one's dead.
二号引擎马上也要熄火了
We'll lose engine two any second.
我们可以迫降了  放松
We can make it in. Easy.
注意减速  不用油  我们滑翔着陆
Pull it back, glide in on fumes.
日本鬼子  着陆点有日本巡逻队
Japs! We got Jap patrols all over the place!
丹尼  到别处降落  坐好了  这会很颠簸
Land somewhere else! Strap yourselves in! We're coming in hard!
我们死定了
We're a deadstick.
离开机头
Get outta the nose!
抓紧了  伙计们!我们开始着陆了!
Hold on, boys! We're going down!
小心树枝!
Watch the trees!
有人受伤吗?
Everyone all right?
我没事儿
I'm OK! I'm OK!
瑞普利呢?
Where's Ripley?
他已死了
He's dead.
注意日本鬼子
Watch for Japs!
日本巡逻队!
Jap patrols!
快找掩体
Take cover!
- 谁还有备用弹匣?  - 我有
- Who's got magazines?  - Got em!
我们要去那边山里找中国人
Gotta get up into those hills, find the Chinese!
我们受到火力压制!
They got us pinned down!
丹尼!雷夫!不!
Danny! Rafe! Rafe, no!
- 丹尼!  - 雷夫  没有救了!
- Danny! - Rafe, you don't have a chance!
天啊  丹尼  快呀
God damn. Danny! Come on!
丹尼!
Danny!
噢  妈的  安东尼死了
Aw, shit, Anthony.
古斯  你听到吗?
Gooz! Can you hear me?
醒醒
Yeah. Come on.
丹尼  放松  放松点
Danny. Easy, easy, easy.
我这次搞砸了
I've had better landings.
你救了我们
You saved us back there.
我脖子受伤了
I got something in my neck.
- 我帮你拔出来  - 古斯在哪儿?
- Let me pull this out. - Where's Gooz?
他没事  他就在那儿
He's fine. He's right over there.
手榴弹!
Grenade!
快趴下!
Get down!
丹尼
Danny!
Danny.
丹尼
Danny!
撑着点  我来了
Hold on! Rafe! Hold on, now. I got you.
你不会有事的
You're all right. You're all right.
我  我不行了
I'm not gonna make it.
你不会死的  看着我  丹尼
Oh, yes, you are. Yes, you are. Now look at me.
雷夫  我好冷  冷极了!
Rafe, I'm so cold. I'm so cold.
你不会有事
You're all right. Hey.
- 雷夫  帮我一个忙  - 什么?
- Hey, Rafe? Can you do me a favor? - What?
你要找别人替我写墓志铭
Can you have someone else write my name on the tombstone?
你不会死  听我说!
You're not gonna die. Look at me,
你不会死的  你听见了吗?
listen to me! You ain't gonna die, you hear me?
丹尼  你不能死  你知道为什么吗?
Danny. Danny, you can't die. You can't die. You know why?
因为你要当爸爸了
Bcause you're gonna be a father.
你快当爸爸了  我本来不该告诉你
You're gonna be a daddy. I wasn't supposed to tell you.
你要当爸爸了
You're gonna be a father.
求求你
Please.
不  你才是
No. You are.
丹尼
Danny.
别死啊  丹尼
Danny? Danny? Please, please!
上帝啊  丹尼
Please. God. Please, Danny.
别开枪  他们是中国人
Hold your fire! They're Chinese.
这次行动结束后回首往事
When the action is over and we look back...
我们感触颇深
we understand both more and less.
有一点是不容置疑的：
This much is certain.
在杜立特轰炸之前  美国人充满了失败的情绪
Before the Doolittle raid... America knew nothing but defeat.
可在此之后  大家都振奋起来
After it, nothing but victory.
日本也首次意识到失败的可能
Japan realized for the first time that
并开始小心起来
they could lose and began to pull back.
我们看到了胜机而加紧步伐
America realized that she would win...
他们终将获胜并开始步步进逼
and surged forward.
这场战争改变了我们和世界
It was a war that changed America and world.
多利・米勒是第一名
Dorie Miller was the first black American to
获得海军十字勋章的黑人
be awarded the Navy Cross.
但获得勋章的不止他一人
But he would not be the last.
他只是英雄群体中的一员
He joined a brotherhood of heroes.
所有参与轰炸的机员同样受勋
That's for all the raiders.
对我们来说  二战始于珍珠港
World War II for us began at Pearl Harbor...
一千一百七十七名官兵  至今仍长眠在亚利桑那号战舰中
and 1,177 men still lie entombed in the battleship Arizona.
我们受到的挫折  使我们变得坚强
America suffered... but America grew stronger.
但这不是必然的结果
It was not inevitable.
危机考验了我们  通过考验我们克服了困难
The times tried our souls and through the trial, we overcame.
嗨!小丹尼  你想飞吗?
Hey, Danny... how'd you like to go flying?
到这来
Come here.
There You'll Be
影片《珍珠港》主题曲
演唱：Faith Hill
当我想起从前 还有
When I think back
On these times，And
那些我们没有完成的梦想
the dreams
We left behind
我很高兴因为在我的生命中
I'll be glad 'cause
I was blessed to
有你是多么幸运
get，To have you in my life
当我回忆过去
When I look back
On these days
眼前就会浮现你的脸庞
I'll look and see your face
你总会在那守候着我
You were right there for me
在我的梦里
In my dreams
我总是看见你架着飞机直冲云霄
I'll always see you soar
Above the sky
在我的心里
In my heart
永远都会有你的一席之地
There always be a place
For you for all my life
我会珍藏对你的记忆
I'll keep a part
Of you with me
不论我去哪里 你都会如影跟随
And everywhere I am
There you'll be
不论我到哪里 你都会相伴相依
And everywhere I am
There you'll be
你让我知道
Well you showed me
How it feels
触摸到头顶的天空是什么感觉
To feel the sky
Within my reach
我会永远记得
And I always
Will remember all
你让我感觉到的精神力量
The strength you
Gave to me
你的爱让我坚持到底
Your love made me
Make it through
这一切都是因为你
Oh, I owe so much to you
你总会在那守候着我
You were right there for me
在我的梦里
In my dreams
我总是看见你架着飞机直冲云霄
I'll always see you soar
Above the sky
在我的心里
In my heart There
永远都会有你的一席之地
always be a place
For you for all my life
我会珍藏对你的记忆
I'll keep a part
Of you with me
不论我到哪里 你都会相伴相依
And everywhere I am
There you'll be
在你身上
'Cause I always saw in you
我能感到力量和生命的意义
My light, my strength
我对你
And I want to thank you
感激不尽
Now for all the ways
你总会在那守候着我
You were right there for me
到永远
For always
在我的梦里
In my dreams
我总是看见你架着飞机直冲云霄
I'll always see you soar
Above the sky
在我的心里
In my heart There
永远都会有你的一席之地
always be a place
For you for all my life
我会珍藏对你的记忆
I'll keep a part
Of you with me
不论我去哪里 你都会如影跟随
And everywhere I am-
There you'll be
不论我到哪里
And everywhere I am
你都会相伴相依
There you'll be
相伴相依